<?xml version="1.0"?>
<GWENG>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0001" type="multi">
    <HEADLINE>TODAY IN HISTORY</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei, Aug. 30 (CNA)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>Today is Monday, Aug. 30, or the 15th
day of the seventh month of the Year of the Monkey according to
the lunar calendar. Following is a list of important events that have
occurred on this date in the past:

30 B.C.: Mark Antony, the ruler of the eastern part of the Roman
Empire, commits suicide at the court of his lover, Cleopatra, queen
of Egypt, who later commits suicide by allowing an asp to bite her
breast.

1483: Louis XI, king of France who was responsible for the
unification of his country after the Hundred Years War, dies and is
succeeded by his son, Charles VIII.

1862: Thomas Jonathan Jackson, known as "Stonewall," American
Confederate general, leads his forces to victory against the Union
Army at the Second Battle of Bull Run in Virginia. He was
accidentally killed by his own troops at Chancellorvile in 1863.

1901: The vacuum cleaner is patented by Scotsman Hubert Cecil
Booth.

1916: Turkey declares war on Romania.

1918: Vladimir Ilich Lenin, known as "Nikolai Lenin," first head
of the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics, is shot and wounded by
Fanya Kaplan and her sister Dora in Moscow.

1928: Jawaharlal Nehru founds the Independence of India League.

1932: Hermann Wilhelm Goering, German Nazi politician and
military leader, is elected president of the German Reichstag. He was
responsible for the buildup of the German air force, directed
Germany's wartime economy and was designated Hitler's successor in
1939.

1937: American boxer Joe Louis flattens Britain's Tommy Farr to
win the heavyweight title at Madison Square Garden in New York.

1940: Sir Joseph John Thomson, British physicist, dies at the age
of 84. He won a Nobel Prize in 1906 for investigating the electrical
conductivity of gases.

1945: Hong Kong is liberated when the British Navy under Rear
Adm. Cecil Harcourt sails into Victoria harbor to accept the Japanese
surrender.

1949: The Southeast China Governor's Office, which was
established in Taipei on Aug. 15, appoints Gen. Sun Li-jen as
commander-in-chief of the Taiwan Garrison Command.

1958: Mainland China's Resolution Concerning the Establishment of
People's Communes in the Rural Areas is promulgated. In a period of
less then three months, 26,578 people's communes involving 127
million peasant household were established all over the mainland.

1963: The "hot line," a direct telephone line between the White
House and the Kremlin linking the US president with the Soviet
leader, becomes operational.

1974: A bomb planted by leftist guerrillas explodes in the main
office of Mitsubishi Heavy Industries at Marunouchi in Tokyo, killing
eight people and injuring 376 others.

1979: Ding Mou-shih, former vice minister of Foreign Affairs,
leaves for Seoul to assume his post as ROC ambassador to the Republic
of Korea.

1981: Muhammad Ali Rajai, president of Iran, and his prime
minister, Mohammed Javad Bahonar, become victims of a bomb planted in
the premier's office in Teheran.

1981: President Chiang Ching-kuo receives US Senator John Glenn.

1988: Republic of China-US talks on finance and banking open in
Washington. The ROC negotiators agree to open the Taiwan market to
credit card companies and to expand credit for foreign banks.

1989: Guatemalan President Marco Vincicio Cerezo Arevalo arrives
in Taipei for a six-day visit.

1990: Chien Mu, a great master in the study of Chinese classics,
dies in Taipei at the age of 96.

1991: Azerbaijan declares independence from the Soviet Union.

1999: New Salvadoran Ambassador Francisco Ricardo Santana Berrios
presents his credentials to President Lee Teng-hui.

1999: Premier Vincent Siew leaves Taipei for Los Angeles en route
to Panama to attend the inauguration of President-elect Mireya
Moscoso on Sept. 1 as the special envoy of President Lee Teng-hui.

2001: President Chen Shui-bian receives Brisbane Mayor Jim
Soorley, and welcomes his visit aimed at strenthening exchanges
between the ROC and Australia.

Confucius' lesson of the day: "Where there is truth, there is
intelligence; where there is intelligence, there is truth."</TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0002" type="multi">
    <HEADLINE>TAIWAN HEADLINE NEWS</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei, Aug. 30 (CNA)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>The lead stories in major Taiwan
dailies on Monday are as follows:

The China Times:

Mainland China unusually cancels its large-scale Dongshan Island
military exercise plan.

The United Daily News:

The New York Times cooperates with the United Daily News in
publishing a special weekly edition in Taipei each Monday.

The Liberty Times:

President Chen will leave for two-country diplomatic tour today.

The Taiwan Daily:

President Chen will highlight Taiwan's separate identity during
his overseas trip.

The Central Daily News:

A KMT lawmaker says Henry Lee's report debunks the 'pan-green'
camp assertion that the March 19 shooting was carried out by the
'pan-blue' alliance.

The China Post:

Henry Lee's report is creating disputes.

The Taiwan News:

Rumors end as Howard fixes Australian poll date.

The Taipei Times:

Chen visits typhoon-hit townships.</TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0003" type="other">
    <HEADLINE>FOREIGN EXCHANGE RATES</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei, Aug. 30 (CNA)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>The exchange rates* for major foreign
currencies quoted in New Taiwan dollars by Chang Hwa Commercial bank
on Monday: 

BUYING RATES     SELLING RATES

US dollar                       33.870          34.270
Euro                            40.43           41.43
Hong Kong dollar                 4.310           4.430
Japanese yen                     0.3068          0.3128
Australian dollar               23.77           23.97
Canadian dollar                 25.80           26.00
Pound sterling                  60.81           61.21
Singapore dollar                19.79           19.99
South African rand               4.96            5.16
Sweden krone                     4.438           4.538
Swiss Franc                     26.46           26.66
Thai baht                        0.8104          0.8304
N. Zealand dollar               22.14           22.34

*  Exchange  rates  for  the  US  dollar  in  amounts  less  than
US$10,000.</TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0004" type="multi">
    <HEADLINE>INTERNATIONAL HEADLINE NEWS</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Bangkok, AUg. 30(CNA)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>Bangkok Post: Apirak win "a blow for government".
The legitmacy and authority given to Apirak Kosayodhin to govern Bangkok
not only means an end to the Democract party's victory drought in the
gubernatorial poll but also indicates that Thai Rak Thai party's iron-fisted
control of power is prised open, political observers said of his resounding
victory yesterday.
(Francis Kuo)</TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0005" type="multi">
    <HEADLINE>INTERNATIONAL HEADLINE NEWS</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Manila, Aug 30(CNA)
(By Emerson T. Lim)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>Manila Bulletin: Gov't, MILF
issue joint statement for peace

Both the government and the Moro Islamic
Liberation Front (MILF) members of the Coordinating
Committee on the Cessation of Hostilities (CCCH)
signed yesterday a joint statement expressing
confidence on the prospects of peace in Mindanao
despite the presence of some contentious issues.

The Philippine Daily Inquirer: Catholic bishop
tells solons: Abstain from pork

GIVE up the pork barrel as part of "fasting on
corruption," Manila Archbishop Gaudencio Rosales
yesterday urged members of Congress amid the growing
public clamor for the lawmakers to forsake their pork
to help government head off economic collapse.

The Philippine Star: Church leader joins 'pork'
fray

Manila Archbishop Gaudencio Rosales called
yesterday for a "fasting on corruption," encouraging
lawmakers to completely give up their pork barrel
allocations because they are a source of temptation.

The Manila Times: Smuggle try at R2 port

An attempt to smuggle in a rice shipment from
Thailand worth P35 million through the Harbor Center
Terminal, a private port in Tondo, Manila, in 2001 was
foiled by Customs authorities, documents ob-tained by
The Manila Times showed.</TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0006" type="multi">
    <HEADLINE>INTERNATIONAL HEADLINE NEWS</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Los Angeles, Aug.29 (CNA)
(By Lu-sheng Chu)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>Los Angeles Times: 
Bush and N.Y. Both in Spotlight.
On the eve of his nominating convention,
President Bush is facing a tighter and tougher
reelection fight than many of his fellow
Republicans expected,elevating the stakes--and
jitters--as Bush heads into one of the most
crucial weeks of his reelection bid.</TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0007" type="multi">
    <HEADLINE>INTERNATIONAL HEADLINE NEWS</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Singapore, Aug. (CNA)
(By Charles Kang)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>The Straits
Times:Singles can buy HDB flats of any size.

New demand and supply patterns allow easing
of rules;PM also addresses concerns of Eurasians
and Indians.

Singles aged 35 and above will now be able
to buy Housing Board flats of any size form the
resale market.

Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong delivered
this piece of good news yesterday as he sought
to address the concerns of groups like the
singles who,he said,felt left out after hearing
his National Day Rally speech.

The Lianhe Zaobao:Singles aged 35 and above
can buy HDB flats of any size.</TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0008" type="multi">
    <HEADLINE>INTERNATIONAL  HEADLINE  NEWS</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Tokyo Aug.30 (CNA)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>The Japan Times: IOC awards Murofushi gold;
Annus stripped of hammer throw title for doping violation.

Japan's Koji Murofushi was awarded the Athens Olympic men'shammer
throw gold medal Sunday after Hungarian winner Adrian Anuus was
stripped of his title for violating doping rules, an Interantional
Olympic Committee official said.</TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0009" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>ATHENS GAMES WRAP UP WITH TAIWAN COMING AWAY WITH BEST RESULT EVER</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Athens,  Aug.  30 (CNA)
(By CNA reporters and Deborah Kuo)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>The 2004 Athens Olympic Games wrapped up
with a closing ceremony at the Olympic Stadium in the Greek capital
Sunday evening after 16 days of competitions among athletes from 201
countries around the world.</P>
      <P>Taiwan came away with a respectable haul -- winning two golds,
two silvers and one bronze medal to take 31st spot in the overall
medal standings. The result was Taiwan's best ever at the Olympics.</P>
      <P>Taekwondo athlete Huang Chih-hsiung, who garnered a silver medal
in the men's 68-kg division, led the Chinese Taipei delegation to the
closing ceremony.</P>
      <P>Addressing the ceremony, International Olympic Committee
President Jacques Rogge described the Athens Games as the
"unforgettable, dream games." Rogge invited all the world's top
athletes to meet again in four years in Beijing for the 29th
Olympiad.</P>
      <P>A few days earlier, the 2004 Athens Olympic Games organizing
committee declared Aug. 26 as "Chinese Taipei Day" after two Taiwan
athletes won gold medals in taekwondo events on that date.</P>
      <P>Chen Shih-hsin, 26, defeated Cuba's Yanelis Yuliet Labrada Diaz
Thursday in the final of the women's under 49-kg Taekwondo division
to win Taiwan's first-ever Olympic gold medal.</P>
      <P>Shortly afterwards, Chu Mu-yen, a 22-year-old male athlete,
grabbed gold in the men's under 58-kg division by defeating Mexican
Oscar Francisco Salazar Blanco.</P>
      <P>It marked the first time that any country has ever won two gold
medals on a single day in taekwondo since it became an Olympic event
12 years ago.</P>
      <P>The head coach of Taiwan's four-member taekwondo team said that
the team's performance was better than expected and that it has
become a source of pride for all the people of Taiwan.</P>
      <P>The Chinese Taipei team also took home a silver medal in men's
archery and a bronze medal in women's archery.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0010" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>TAIWAN NATIONAL POLICY ADVISER DELIVERS SPEECH IN OSAKA</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Tokyo,  Aug. 30 (CNA)
(By Perry Hsieh and Sofia Wu)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>Hsiao Hsin-huang, a national policy adviser
in Taiwan, delivered a speech in Osaka Monday on Taiwan's democratic
development over the past two decades and the gist of the
Republic of China's policy toward mainland China.</P>
      <P>Hsiao told the 300-plus audience members that maintaining peace
in the Taiwan Strait has consistently been Taiwan's top mainland
policy goal.</P>
      <P>The lecture meeting was organized by the western Japan chapter of
the Global Alliance for Democracy and Peace. The conference goers
included representatives of Taiwanese communities in major western
Japanese cities, such as Osaka, Kobe, Kyoto and Nagoya, as well as
Japanese officials, scholars and business leaders.</P>
      <P>In his view, Hsiao said, democracy is a cornerstone for permanent
cross-strait peace.</P>
      <P>Noting that the people on both sides of the Taiwan Strait have a
common interest in peace, democracy and economic prosperity, Hsiao
said Taiwan will do its utmost to maintain peace in the Taiwan
Strait.</P>
      <P>Hsiao said Taiwan also earnestly hopes that mainland China can
learn from the ROC's experience in carrying out democratic reform
over the past two decades.</P>
      <P>Mainland China's democratization will contribute to regional
peace, security and prosperity, Hsiao added.</P>
      <P>He also called on Taiwan expatriates in Japan and the Japanese
government to assist Taiwan in gaining representation in the United
Nations, the World Health Organization and other major international
bodies.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0011" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>HENRY LEE'S 319 SHOOTING REPORT REACHES TOP PROSECUTOR'S OFFICE</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei, Aug. 30 (CNA)
(By Deborah Kuo)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>The much-awaited report on the presidential
election-eve shooting of President Chen Shui-bian and Vice President
Annette Lu just completed by world-renowned forensic scientist Dr.
Henry Lee was sent from New York to the office of Taiwan's top
prosecutor Monday.</P>
      <P>The report package, bound with an "evidence security seal" upon
the conclusion of a news conference at a hotel in Flushing, New York,
Saturday presided over by Lee, contains the 130-page report, 150
photographs, an optical disc and a letter from Lee to State Public
Prosecutor-General Lu Ren-fa.</P>
      <P>The package was received by Taiwan's chief liaison official in
New York, Andrew Hsia, and then delivered via diplomatic post to the
Ministry of Foreign Affairs in Taipei before reaching Lu's office.</P>
      <P>While outlining the report at the news conference in New York,
Lee, who visited Taiwan April 9-11 to examine the wounds of the
president and vice president and to inspect the scene of the March 19
shooting, claimed that the election-eve shooting was not a political
assassination attempt because had it been, the shooter would have
used a more powerful weapon.</P>
      <P>Lee quoted the report as concluding that his Connecticut
laboratory team, which traveled to Taiwan with him April 9-11,
discovered special "tool marks" on the shell casing retrieved from
the scene of the shooting.</P>
      <P>This, he said, could be a lead for investigators in Taiwan to
follow toward solving who pulled the trigger.</P>
      <P>At the press conference, Lee suggested that Taiwan law
enforcement officials continue to aggressively search for and seize
all illegal firearms in the country and "examine and compare all the
guns."</P>
      <P>Lee suggested that authorities discover exactly where such a gun
that was used in the shooting could have been made.</P>
      <P>He also suggested that all the videotapes of the event should be
re-examined to positively identify the position of the "hot zone"
where the shooter would have been standing.</P>
      <P>"Let the evidence talk. What counts is the evidence, and it has
nothing to do with politics, motives nor investigations," Lee said.</P>
      <P>Lee added that there are still many unanswered questions
surrounding the shooting because there are so many "unknown factors."</P>
      <P>"Unknown factors," Lee said, include the uncertainty of the exact
location of where the shell casing actually came to rest after being
removed or ejected from the gun, the location of which is still in
question; and the amount and composition of the gunpowder used in the
bullet.</P>
      <P>Lee added that re-enactments of the shooting carried out when he
and his team were in Taiwan were only speculative and are of little
value without possession of the actual weapon used and a clear
understanding of where the shooter was on the street.</P>
      <P>He reiterated, however, that the tool marks on the shell casing
did give investigators a place to start.</P>
      <P>Lee added that the motive for the shooting could become clear
once the actual weapon and shooter are found.</P>
      <P>He called for the Taiwan public to remain calm and sensible when
considering the incident.</P>
      <P>When asked about the recent creation of a special "truth
investigation commission" by Taiwan's opposition-controlled
legislature, Lee urged Taiwan "to listen to the truth and give law
enforcement authorities some leeway and let investigators do their
jobs."</P>
      <P>The opposition "pan-blue alliance" of the Kuomintang (KMT) and
the People First Party held a series of rallies, including one on
April 10 that ended violently, after the March 20 election to protest
what they perceived as an "unfair election" marred by voting
irregularities and the "bogus" shooting that gave the incumbent
president sympathy votes.</P>
      <P>Chen beat his competitor, KMT Chairman Lien Chan, by only 29,518
votes out of the more than 13 million ballots cast.</P>
      <P>The weapon used in the shooting has never been recovered, and no
suspects have been brought in by police.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0012" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>CHEN ENDORSES CABINET DECISION TO SEND '319' BILL BACK TO LEGISLATURE</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei, Aug. 30 (CNA)
(By Sofia Wu)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>President Chen Shui-bian on Monday endorsed
the Cabinet's decision to send the controversial "March 19 Shooting
Truth Investigation Special Committee Statute" back to the
Legislative Yuan for reconsideration.</P>
      <P>The Cabinet decided Friday to send the statute back to the
legislature for reconsideration, in effect vetoing the legislation,
on the grounds that the statute violates the principle of division of
powers and that the special committee to be established under the
statute to investigate the presidential election-eve shooting of
President Chen and Vice President Annette Lu would usurp the powers
of the Judicial Yuan and the Control Yuan.</P>
      <P>According to Article 3 of the Additional Articles of the ROC
Constitution, the statute will now be referred to the legislature for
reconsideration after the Cabinet's reconsideration request was
approved by the president.</P>
      <P>If the reconsideration request is rejected by the legislature,
the statute will then return to the executive branch where it must be
signed into law by the president.</P>
      <P>According to the Constitution, the Cabinet, with the approval of
the president, can return a bill passed by the legislature within 10
days. The legislature has to handle the reconsideration request
within 15 days after it is received. If the Cabient delivers such a
request during the legislative recess, the legislature has to convene
within seven days and must make a decision within 15 days after
convening.</P>
      <P>To override the Cabinet's veto and uphold the original statute,
at least 109 lawmakers -- a simple majority of the 217 seats in the
225-seat legislature that are presently filled -- have to vote
infavor of the statute; otherwise, the statute will be invalidated.</P>
      <P>Premier Yu Shyi-kun said last week that in light of the fact that
the opposition "pan-blue alliance" of the Kuomintang and the People
First Party jointly control a slim majority in the legislature, the
alliance might succeed in upholding the statute.</P>
      <P>Nevertheless, Yu said, the Cabinet has to show it has done its
part by pointing out the unconstitutionality of the statute. He urged
the Legislative Yuan to shoulder the historic nature of the statute
and rescind it.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0013" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>NEW KMT REFORM-MINDED SUBGROUP TO TACKLE PARTY NOMINATION SYSTEM</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei, Aug. 30 (CNA)
(By Deborah Kuo)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>A new subgroup of the opposition Kuomintang
(KMT) comprised of "young reform-minded lawmakers with high
educational backgrounds and crystal integrity" will be inaugurated
Sept. 2 to serve as a "clear stream" in Taiwan's politics.</P>
      <P>KMT Legislator Apollo Chen, one of the three co-founders of the
group, tentatively named the Taiwan New Hope Link, said that the
group has set several major objectives as their immediate tasks,
including pushing for intra-party reforms within the KMT and keeping
a closer eye on the Democratic Progressive Party-ruled
administration.</P>
      <P>Chen said the group's first goal will be to tackle the KMT's
nomination system for legislative elections, the next of which will
be held this December.</P>
      <P>Chen said that the Taiwan New Hope Link, which is expected to be
comprised of 15 KMT legislators representing roughly each of the
major constituencies nationwide, will propose to the KMT
decision-making body that the nomination of the party's
legislators-at-large should be more open to allow more KMT members to
voice their opinions on the selections.</P>
      <P>He claimed that the existing nomination mechanism -- the KMT
decision-making body first draws up a recommended shortlist of
candidates which is then passed by a vote of KMT Central Committee
members -- is not only partial but also lacks the spirit of
democracy.</P>
      <P>Chen said the Taiwan New Hope Link will suggest that elected
representatives, like all KMT legislators, be allowed to have a say
in the nominations to better reflect the wishes of all KMT members
and supporters.</P>
      <P>Legislator Lee Chia-chin, another co-founder of the KMT subgroup,
noted that the potential KMT legislator-at-large nominees should be
given a "test run" by speaking in a platform presentation so that all
KMT members as well as voters can better understand their stances on
a variety of issues.</P>
      <P>Legislator Chuo Po-yuan, the third co-founder, said that on the
shortlist of KMT legislators-at-large there should be representatives
from more groups and from more walks of life to deepen the essence of
representation.</P>
      <P>Members of the soon-to-be-established Taiwan New Hope Link will
have an average age of 42 and will each have more than 10 years'
experience in politics, Chen said.</P>
      <P>He claimed that the group members all have enviable academic
backgrounds and are in good social standing, and will be the "new
hope of Taiwan."</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0014" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>TAIPEI SHARES PRICES END LOWER</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug. 30 (CNA)
(By Nick Huang)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>Shares prices on the Taiwan Stock Exchange
opened low and closed lower Monday, with the weighted index, the
market's key barometer, dropping 8.77 points to close at 5,788.94
points.</P>
      <P>The bourse opened at 5,791.87 and fluctuated between 5,819.34 and
5,771.03 during the day's trading.</P>
      <P>Trading decreased slightly, with 3.09 billion shares changing
hands on a market turnover of NT$66.02 billion (US$1.93 billion).</P>
      <P>Seven of the eight major stock categories gained ground, with
cement stocks moving up the most by 3.1 percent, followed by
construction issues by 2.6 percent, paper and pulp issues by 1.5
percent, textile stocks by 1.1 percent, foodstuff issues by 0.8
percent, banking and financial shares by 0.5 percent and plastics and
chemicals by 0.3 percent.</P>
      <P>The remaining stock category -- machinery and electronics shares
-- remained unchanged.</P>
      <P>Losers outnumbered gainers 371 to 323, with 181 stocks remaining
unchanged.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0015" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>CLA PUBLISHES NEW WORK MANUAL FOR FOREIGN LABORERS IN 5 LANGUAGES</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug.  30 (CNA)
(By Sofia Wu)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>The Council of Labor Affairs (CLA) said
Monday it has published five bilingual editions of a new work manual
for foreign laborers and caregivers to help them understand
regulations relating to them and to adapt to the lifestyle in Taiwan.</P>
      <P>Five bilingual editions of the new work manual -- Chinese-Thai,
Chinese-English, Chinese-Vietnamese, Chinese-Indonesian and
Chinese-Mongolian -- are now available, CLA officials said.</P>
      <P>In addition to individual foreign workers, the officials said,
the new manual will be also distributed to various relevant
authorities and groups, including the Bureau of Consular Affairs
under the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, representative offices of
foreign workers' countries of origin, manpower associations, the
Economic Processing Zone Administration, the Hsinchu Science-based
Industrial Park Administration, city and county governments and
police bureaus, the Aviation Police Bureau and foreign laborers
detention centers.</P>
      <P>With a view to helping foreign workers better understand Taiwan's
regulations governing foreign laborers, housemaids or caregivers and
their rights and benefits during their stay in Taiwan, CLA officials
said the council will ask foreign labor-exporting countries to
incorporate the CLA-compiled new work manual into their pre-job
training courses for their citizens intending to travel to Taiwan for
work.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0016" type="multi">
    <HEADLINE>INTERNATIONAL HEADLINE NEWS</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Washington,  Aug. 30 (CNA)
(By Jorge Liu)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>Washington Post: Republican Convention
Opens With 9/11 Focus; Cheney Lauds Bush For War Leadership.

Vice President Cheney launched the Republican convention Sunday
in a speech hailing President Bush's war leadership, as more than
200,000 demonstrators took to the streets here in protest of the Bush
administration's policies.</TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0017" type="multi">
    <HEADLINE>INTERNATIONAL HEADLINE NEWS</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Moscow,  Aug.  30 (CNA)
(By Vlogya Chang)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>The Moscow Times: Explosion Tarnishes
Chechen Election.

A man blew himself up as he fled a polling station in central
Grozny on Sunday in the only violence to tarnish Chechnya's election
for a president to replace slain leader Akhmad Kadyrov.</TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0018" type="multi">
    <HEADLINE>INTERNATIONAL HEADLINE NEWS</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>London,  Aug. 30 (CNA)
(By N.K. Han)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>The Times: Comedy rules as BBC turns back
on reality TV.

The new Director-General of the BBC's vision for the future
breaks from the philosophies of former director-generals and sounds
the death knell for makeover programmes.

Financial Times: Over 100,000 protesters March in New York
Against Bush policies.

Thousands of placard-waving marchers on Sunday snaked through the
streets of Manhattan in a boisterous, yet orderly, demonstration
against the policies of the administration of President George W.
Bush.</TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0019" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>PROSECUTOR-GENERAL OFFICE RECAPS ILLEGAL FIREARMS ROUNDUP</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei, Aug. 30 (CNA)
(By Deborah Kuo)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>Police have made 569 raids around Taiwan in
search of places manufacturing illegal firearms since the
presidential election-eve shooting of President Chen Shui-bian and
Vice President Annette Lu on March 19, officials from Taiwan's top
prosecutor's office reported Monday.</P>
      <P>Officials from the State Public Prosecutor-General's Office said
that no weapons or suspects that could be connected with the shooting
have been found.</P>
      <P>The officials were responding to a suggestion offered in a newly
released report by a team led by forensic scientist Henry Lee that
police in Taiwan ought to try to find the workshop that produced the
homemade gun used in the shooting.</P>
      <P>Officials also said that after careful examination of all the
available videos of the "hot zone" where the perpetrator of the
shooting was most likely standing, police have identified 46
potential suspects, with 13 people yet to be identified.</P>
      <P>Police have also investigated 4,824 people who have previous
criminal records for firearms smuggling or trading.</P>
      <P>Of these, 4,636 have been found to be unrelated to the shooting
and 188 people have yet to be located.</P>
      <P>As of last week, the officials said, 244 firearms of various
types have been examined, while 12 bullets have been found to be
identical in structure with the one found in President Chen's jacket
the day he was shot.</P>
      <P>Henry Lee's report, bound with an "evidence security seal" and
containing 130 pages of written accounts, 150 photographs, a disc and
a letter from Lee to State Public Prosecutor-General Lu Ren-fa, was
sent from New York to Lu's office Monday.</P>
      <P>While outlining the report at a news conference in New York
Saturday, Lee, who visited Taiwan April 9-11 to examine the wounds of
the president and vice president and to inspect the scene of the
March 19 shooting, claimed that the election-eve shooting was not a
political assassination attempt because had it been, the shooter
would have used a more powerful weapon.</P>
      <P>Lee quoted his report as concluding that his Connecticut
laboratory team, which traveled to Taiwan with him April 9-11,
discovered special "tool marks" on the shell casing retrieved from
the scene of the shooting.</P>
      <P>This, he said, could be a lead for investigators in Taiwan to
follow toward determining who pulled the trigger.</P>
      <P>At the press conference, Lee suggested that Taiwan law
enforcement officials continue to aggressively search for and seize
all illegal firearms in the country and "examine and compare all the
guns."</P>
      <P>Lee suggested that authorities discover exactly where such a gun
that was used in the shooting could have been made.</P>
      <P>He also suggested that all the videotapes of the event should be
re-examined to positively identify the position of the "hot zone"
where the shooter would have been standing.</P>
      <P>"Let the evidence talk. What counts is the evidence, and it has
nothing to do with politics, motives nor investigations," Lee said.</P>
      <P>Lee added that there are still many unanswered questions
surrounding the shooting because there are so many "unknown factors."</P>
      <P>"Unknown factors," Lee said, include the uncertainty of the exact
location of where the shell casing actually came to rest after being
removed or ejected from the gun, the location of which is still in
question; and the amount and composition of the gunpowder used in the
bullet.</P>
      <P>Lee added that the motive for the shooting could become clear
once the actual weapon and shooter are found.</P>
      <P>When asked about the recent creation of a special "truth
investigation commission" by Taiwan's opposition-controlled
legislature, Lee urged Taiwan "to listen to the truth and give law
enforcement authorities some leeway and let investigators do their
jobs."</P>
      <P>The opposition "pan-blue alliance" of the Kuomintang (KMT) and
the People First Party held a series of rallies, including one on
April 10 that ended violently, after the March 20 election to protest
what they perceived as an "unfair election" marred by voting
irregularities and the "bogus" shooting that gave the incumbent
president sympathy votes.</P>
      <P>Chen beat his competitor, KMT Chairman Lien Chan, by only 29,518
votes out of the more than 13 million ballots cast.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0020" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>AUTO/SPACE RATIO IN TAIPEI CITY LOWERED TO 1.04:1, SAYS MAYOR MA</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei, Aug. 30 (CNA)
(By Deborah Kuo)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>It may be hard to believe, but the parking
situation is Taipei City is improving, according to the mayor, who
opened a public parking lot in the Hsinyi district Monday.</P>
      <P>Mayor Ma Ying-jeou said the ratio of automobiles to parking
spaces in Taipei City has been lowered to 1.04: 1 this year. The
ratio in 1998 was 1.24: 1, Ma said.</P>
      <P>Parking will be free before Sept. 15 at the Chunguang Car Park,
where 213 spaces for automobiles and 71 spaces for motorbikes are
available.</P>
      <P>Ma said that currently there are about 380,000 parking spaces
around Taipei City, including 300,000 private ones in or besides
buildings and 80,000 public ones operated by the city government.</P>
      <P>Four hundred spaces for cars have been turned into parking for
motorbikes since he became mayor, Ma said.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0021" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>CHINA STEEL SETS RECORD EARNING FOR FIRST HALF</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug.  30 (CNA)
(By Flor Wang)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>China Steel Corporation (CSC) posted a
record high pre-tax profit of NT$28.295 billion in the first half of
this year, a 27.04 percent growth over the previous year's level on a
business revenue of NT$76.144 billion (US$2.23 billion) , a CSC
spokesman reported Monday.</P>
      <P>The first-half profit figure accounted for 47.5 percent of the
company's target set for the whole of 2004, with pre-tax earning per
share hitting NT$2.99.</P>
      <P>As the CSC has raised its product prices for the third and fourth
quarters, an average increase of more than NT$1,500 per metric ton,
the company is confident of achieving the full-year profit aim of
NT$59.5 billion, the spokesman said.</P>
      <P>Because of the price hikes, the Taiwan's largest steel maker
started to make greater profits in July, with its gross earning ratio
last month already reaching 40.7 percent, a noticeable rise from
January's 35.16 percent, he noted.</P>
      <P>As the effects of mainland China's move to cool off its economy
have gradually loosened, demand for steel from home and abroad will
rebound, further pushing up CSC's earnings, he said, adding that the
company is hopeful of chalking up a whole-year profit of over NT$59.5
billion and obtaining a new high in earnings per share of NT$6.29.</P>
      <P>The Cabinet-level Directorate General of Budget, Accounting and
Statistics has recently adjusted upward its forecast for Taiwan's
economic growth rate for 2004 to 5.87 percent, the largest increase
in nearly seven years.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0022" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>PRICES MIXED ON TAIPEI FUTURES MARKET</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug.  30 (CNA)
(By Huang Kwang-chun)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>Prices on Taipei's stock futures market
recorded mixed results Monday as the Taiwan Stock Exchange (TAIEX)
Capitalization Weighted Index for September fell 25 points to close
at 5,785, with 18,023 contracts changing hands.</P>
      <P>TAIEX Index futures for October lost 12 points to finish at
5,775, with 123 contracts traded, while December futures gave up 10
points to finish at 5,740, with three contracts traded.</P>
      <P>March futures dipped 25 points to close at 5,717, with eight
contracts traded, while June futures gained 23 points to end at
5,730, with seven contracts traded.</P>
      <P>Taiwan International Mercantile Exchange reference levels for
TAIEX Index futures trading were set Monday at 5,810 for September,
5,787 for October, 5,750 for December, 5,742 for March and 5,707 for
June.</P>
      <P>Electronics (TE) and financial (TF) futures, which are sub-index
futures based on Taiwan Stock Exchange-listed electronics shares and
financial stocks, were also mixed.</P>
      <P>September TE futures dropped 2.95 points to close at 225.05, with
2,718 contracts traded, while October TE futures dipped 0.8 points to
finish at 225.3, with 64 contracts transacted.</P>
      <P>December TE futures fell 0.1 points to finish at 225, with two
contracts traded, while March futures fell 1.5 points to close at
222.5, with two contracts traded.</P>
      <P>No transactions were recorded for other months.</P>
      <P>September TF futures gained 0.2 points to end at 944, with 2,247
contracts changing hands, while October TF futures gave up 0.2 points
to end at 934.4, with 99 contracts traded.</P>
      <P>December TF futures rose 2 points to close at 930.8, with 10
contract transactions, while March TF futures gained 9.8 points to
close at 933.6, with two contracts traded.</P>
      <P>No transactions were recorded for other months.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0023" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>U.S. DOLLAR RISES ON TAIPEI FOREX</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei, Aug. 30 (CNA)
(By Nick Huang)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>The U.S. dollar rose against the new Taiwan
dollar on the Taipei Foreign Exchange Monday, gaining NT$0.014 to
close at NT$34.079.</P>
      <P>A total of US$408 million changed hands.</P>
      <P>The U.S. currency opened at NT$34.065 and fluctuated between
NT$33.990 and NT$34.092 during the day's trading.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0024" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>U.S. CONTAINER SECURITY DELEGATION ARRIVES FOR CONSULTATIONS</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug. 30 (CNA)
(By Sofia Wu)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>A delegation of technical consultants from
the U.S. Homeland Security Department arrived in Taipei Monday in
preparation for implementing container security measures at Kaohsiung
Harbor in southern Taiwan.</P>
      <P>The American Institute in Taiwan (AIT) , which represents U.S.
interests in Taipei in the absence of formal diplomatic ties, said
delegation members will meet with Taiwan's customs officials and
other law enforcement officers in Taipei and Kaohsiung to discuss
details regarding implementation of the U.S.-initiated container
security plan.</P>
      <P>The U.S. government began to implement the plan after the 911
terrorist attacks in New York and Washington, D.C. in 2001, with an
aim to preventing large-scale smuggling of weapons of mass
destruction via containers, AIT officials said.</P>
      <P>Noting that Kaohsiung is the fourth-largest port handling goods
shipped to the United States via containers, AIT officials said the
U.S. government attaches great importance to the security plan for
Kaohsiung Harbor.</P>
      <P>The United States has implemented container security measures at
more than 20 foreign ports around the world, including nine in Asia.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0025" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>MND CLOSELY MONITORING MAINLAND TROOP MOVEMENTS IN WAKE OF PULLOUT</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei, Aug. 30 (CNA)
(By Flor Wang)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>The Ministry of National Defense (MND) will
continue closely monitoring mainland troop movements in the wake of a
report about mainland China's troop pullout from an island in the
Taiwan Strait prior to a scheduled war game, MND officials said
Monday.</P>
      <P>According to information reaching the MND, about 3,000 troops
that were deployed since the middle of this month on Dongshan Island
of Fujian province, which is located opposite Taiwan, have been
withdrawn recently, the officials said.</P>
      <P>The reasons behind the move remain unknown and it is not clear
whether the mainland has effectively canceled its annual sea, land
and air joint military exercises planned for September on the island,
the officials said, adding that the possibility of an emergency
deployment cannot be ruled out for the time being.</P>
      <P>They said that the MND is keeping a close watch on the movements
of mainland troops and that it will step up information exchanges
with other countries.</P>
      <P>The People's Liberation Army was to have carried out its eighth
annual military drill on Dongshan Island in September, which was to
have been a mock attack of Taiwan.</P>
      <P>Mainland China and Taiwan split in 1949 at the end of a civil
war.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0026" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>MAY 17 STATEMENT SET M'LAND CHINA'S TONE TOWARD TAIWAN: MAC</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei, Aug. 30 (CNA)
(By Lilian Wu)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>A statement released May 17 by mainland
China has set the tone for China's current policy toward Taiwan, the
Mainland Affairs Council (MAC) said Monday.</P>
      <P>An MAC official made the remarks in a council meeting to analyze
mainland China's overall situation during the second quarter of this
year.</P>
      <P>Liu Teh-shun, MAC vice chairman, noted that Beijing's statement
was issued three days before the inauguration of President Chen
Shui-bian for his second term May 20 this year.</P>
      <P>It is generally believed that Beijing was using the
carrot-and-stick approach in the statement. It sternly warned Taiwan
against moving toward independence and at the same time offered
incentives such as the resumption of cross-strait talks to establish
a mutually trustworthy military framework as well as substantial
trade benefits, such as allowing Taiwan agricultural products to be
shipped to mainland China if only it recognizes the two sides of the
Taiwan Strait as belong to one China.</P>
      <P>Liu said that the council believes that the May 17 statement set
Beijing's basic tone for Taiwan. On the one hand, it makes the
recognition of "one China" the premise of easing cross-strait
relations, and on the other hand, it wants to deflate international
concerns about Chen's second inaugural address.</P>
      <P>Also, mainland China has recently stepped up it efforts to woo
away diplomatic allies of the Republic of China, a situation that Liu
said is a matter of concern.</P>
      <P>On mainland China's economy, Liu noted that its economic growth
in the second quarter was 9.7 percent. With imports and exports as
well as foreign investments continuing to increase, the State Council
has tried to cool down the overheated economy, curb the scale of
credit expansion, and use trade and industrial policies in an attempt
to give its economy a "soft landing."</P>
      <P>On its foreign relations, Liu said that mainland China has
continued to step up its diplomatic work after the expansion of the
European Union to 25 countries in May. Chinese President Hu Jintao,
National People's Congress Chairman Wu Bangguo and Premier Wen Jiabao
all visited Europe in recent months.</P>
      <P>Mainland Chinese leaders have also stepped up their lobbying of
the United States and the EU to grant China full market economy
status.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0027" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>NUMBER OF DENGUE FEVER CASES CLIMBS TO 16 IN TAIWAN</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug. 30 (CNA)
(By Nick Huang)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>The number of dengue fever cases in Taiwan
climbed to 16 as a new case was reported to the Center for Disease
Control (CDC) on Aug. 13, CDC officials said Monday.</P>
      <P>The new patient is a 65-year-old man from Pingtung City,
according to the director of the center's epidemic prevention
section, Lee Tsui-chiung.</P>
      <P>Since dengue fever is transmitted by mosquitoes, CDC officials
are calling on residents to frequently empty containers that could
hold rainwater because standing water is the breeding ground for
mosquitoes. Homeowners can face fines of NT$10,000 to NT$150,000
(US$294 to US$4,410) if they refuse to improve the environment in
their areas.</P>
      <P>Meanwhile, health workers will go to areas suspected of harboring
the kind of mosquito that carries the disease and spray insecticide.</P>
      <P>Also, travelers to southeast Asian countries should be on high
alert against the disease, CDC officials said.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0028" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>RESERVISTS TO HOLD TRAINING DRILL IN SEPTEMBER: MND</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei, Aug. 30 (CNA)
(By Sofia Wu)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>The Ministry of National Defense (MND) said
Monday that the Tung Hsin 16 training drill for reservists is
scheduled to be held in September simultaneously with the Wan An 27
civil defense drill.</P>
      <P>The annual Tung Hsin training exercise was originally scheduled
for July, but was postponed to September due to the extensive
devastation to mountainous regions caused by typhoon Mindulle in
early July, an MND official said.</P>
      <P>In addition to testing the reserve forces' mobilization and
tactical combat prowess, the Tung Hsin drill will also include
homeland security protection measures together with civil defense
forces, who will take part in the Wan An exercise.</P>
      <P>The exact date for this year's Tung Hsin and Wan An exercises
will be announced at a later date, the official said.</P>
      <P>In the past, the Wan An drill usually focused on civil
air-defense and natural disaster prevention, as well as post-disaster
relief and rehabilitation.</P>
      <P>This time around, the official said, the training exercise will
include anti-terrorist operations, tackling of nuclear accidents,
first-aid treatment, anti-air raid measures and other civil defense
tactics.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0029" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>SPECIAL POLICE FORCE HOLDS ANTI-KIDNAPPING EXERCISE</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug.  30 (CNA)
(By Lilian Wu)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>A rapid deployment special police force
conducted its first anti-kidnapping exercise Monday in Kaohsiung,
southern Taiwan.</P>
      <P>Following a botched attempt to capture a notorious wanted
criminal in early August, a fiasco that highlighted the embarrassing
fact that gangsters may possess more powerful arms than the police,
the military has transferred some heavy equipment to the newly
inaugurated special force -- including armored vehicles, the
military Hummers, helicopters, as well as submachine guns.</P>
      <P>In the exercise held in the marine combat arena at the Tsoying
naval base, heavily equipped police first threw stun grenades under
the cover of armored vehicles and helicopters, with sharpshooters
perched on high ground monitoring the situation. Police then
gradually zeroed in on the hideouts of the "criminals, " forcing them
to surrender even with their powerful weaponry.</P>
      <P>Minister of the Interior Su Jia-chyuan, National Police
Administrator Hsieh Yin-tang and Criminal Investigation Bureau chief
Ho You-yi, as well as local police chiefs from around the island,
witnessed the drill.</P>
      <P>Su, who presided over the exercise, said the special quick
response police force will be stationed in Taipei, Taichung and
Kaohsiung and will be tasked with responding to major criminal cases
such as kidnappings or firefights in local cities and counties.</P>
      <P>He expressed appreciation for the equipment and training provided
by the military.</P>
      <P>In the future, international anti-terrorist experts will be
invited to come to Taiwan to help upgrade the abilities of the
police, Su added.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0030" type="multi">
    <HEADLINE>INTERNATIONAL HEADLINE NEWS</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>New York,  Aug.  30 (CNA)
(By Lillian Lin)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>New York Times: The G.O.P. Arrives,
putting Sept. 11 into August.

Republican leaders said Sunday that they would repeatedly remind
the nation of the Sept. 11 attacks as their convention is opening in
New York City Monday for four days. Party aides said the convention
would begin with an elaborate tribute to Sept. 11 victims with
speeches by Senator John McCain and former Mayor Rudolph W. Giuliani,
reminding voters of Mr. Bush's role in leading the nation after the
attacks.

Wall Street Journal: Bush's big priority; energize conservative
Christian base.

In the tight 2004 race, no group is more important to Mr. Bush
than evangelicals and Christian conservatives. As Republicans gather
for their national convention in New York starting Monday, these
religious conservatives are at the heart of a Bush campaign that is
turning traditional general-election strategy on its head. Instead of
focusing on undecided swing voters, Bush advisers are putting top
priority on maximizing voter turnout among conservative
constituencies already disposed to back the president.</TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0031" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>MOFA DENIES REPORTS OF INFORMATION LEAK AT SEOUL REP OFFICE</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei, Aug. 30 (CNA)
(By Sofia Wu)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>The Ministry of Foreign Affairs (MOFA) said
Monday that no abnormalities have been found in the communications
system at the Republic of China's representative office in South
Korea.</P>
      <P>MOFA spokesman Michel C.L. Lu was responding to media reports
that the Seoul office might have been bugged and that some secret
files at the office might have been stolen.</P>
      <P>Lu said a delegation of MOFA officials and operatives with the
Ministry of Justice Investigation Bureau (MJIB) traveled to Seoul two
weeks ago to conduct a regular check on the office's communications
system and espionage prevention measures.</P>
      <P>"Initial reports furnished by the delegation to the MOFA show
that no abnormalities have been discovered in our Seoul office's
communications and information storage systems," Lu said, adding that
the delegation will produce a formal report Sept. 3.</P>
      <P>Lu said the content of the formal report is not expected to
differ from the preliminary one.</P>
      <P>As to media reports about alleged embezzlement of the
representative office's property by former staff members, Lu
dismissed the reports as untrue.</P>
      <P>According to Lu, the MOFA arranged for four experts from the
National Property Bureau to visit Seoul in April this year to check
the representative office's assets and property.</P>
      <P>"The four experts didn't discover any irregularities or
abnormalities during their investigation," Lu said.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0032" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>PREMIER RECEIVES NEW MALAWI AMBASSADOR</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug.  30 (CNA)
(By Huang Kwang-chun)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>Premier Yu Shyi-kun received new Malawi
Ambassador Thengo Maloya at the Executive Yuan Monday and expressed
hope that Republic of China-Malawi relations will be further
strengthened.</P>
      <P>Yu noted that the ROC and Malawi have maintained diplomatic ties
for 38 years and said that the friendship between the two countries
continues to increase.</P>
      <P>He also thanked Malawi for its support for the ROC in the
international arena and expressed his confidence in Maloya's ability
to promote bilateral ties.</P>
      <P>In response, Maloya promised Yu that he will do his best to
promote ROC-Malawi relations and he thanked Yu for the assistance the
ROC has extended to his country.</P>
      <P>Many cooperation programs between the two countries have made
great contributions to Malawi's development and its people's
wellbeing, Maloya noted, adding that he hopes the cooperation will be
further enhanced, particularly in the economic field.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0033" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>PRESIDENT CALLS FOR GIVING NATURE RESPITE</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug. 30 (CNA)
(By Maubo Chang)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>President Chen Shui-bian inspected Monday
an operation to build a temporary bridge over a stream in Hsinyi,
Nantou County, during which he called on developers to give nature
some respite.</P>
      <P>The bridge on the new central cross island highway was supposed
to be finished later that day. while the whole highway, which closed
after July 2 flooding, will reopen for traffic Sept. 4.</P>
      <P>Expressing his thanks to workers on the site, the president said
experts are still contemplating whether the central cross-island
highway, which has been disrupted by mudslides in many places, should
be restored, and he added that humans should give time to let nature
to recover from the disaster.</P>
      <P>He told local officials who pestered him for more financial aid
to rebuild infrastructure in their districts to give up the concept
that people can conquer nature, claiming that many of the disasters
triggered by the flood were part of a backlash by nature to excessive
development.</P>
      <P>Chen said the Executive Yuan will assess the local officials'
requests after taking into account the impact of reconstruction on
the environment.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0034" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>INCREASED CROSS-STRAIT EXCHANGES PRIORITY FOR 2005: CABINET</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug.  30 (CNA)
(By Lilian Wu)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>The Executive Yuan said Monday that
increased cross-Taiwan Strait exchanges and cooperation, as well as
speedier economic transformation will be among six priorities for
next year.</P>
      <P>The Executive Yuan made the remarks when it presented its overall
budget for 2005 to the Legislative Yuan for review. The legislature
will open in mid-September.</P>
      <P>The Executive Yuan said that in 2005, it will continue to work
toward cross-strait cooperation and exchanges so as to strengthen
national security. It will also improve its research and development
ability for industrial development and will continue to promote
financial reforms.</P>
      <P>The other three priorities will be to establish a life-long
learning education network, restructure government organizations and
upgrade social security so as to safeguard social justice.</P>
      <P>In explaining the budget, the Executive Yuan said its work next
year will revolve around several major items, including solidifying
the national identity and building a "normal" government.</P>
      <P>It said that to break out of the diplomatic blockage by mainland
China, it will insist on the safeguarding of its sovereign national
status, on the peace and stability in the Taiwan Strait and on the
country's participation in international peace efforts to shoulder
its responsibility as a member of international society.</P>
      <P>The Cabinet also said that government reforms will lay the basis
for upgrading national competitiveness, adding that in the future, it
will continue to work toward the management of government
organizations and staff, so as to cut the personnel burden of the
government and upgrade its efficiency.</P>
      <P>According to the budget proposal submitted to the legislature,
the government will have revenues of NT$1.4027 trillion (US$41.25
billion) in 2005 and expenditure of NT$1.6356 trillion, with a
shortfall of NT$232.9 billion.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0035" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>CABINET'S BUDGET PROGRAM SUBMITTED FOR LEGISLATIVE SCREENING</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug.  30 (CNA)
(By Flor Wang)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>The Executive Yuan's budget program was
sent Monday to the Legislative Yuan, which will begin screening the
government's 2005 expenditure and revenue once it opens its new
session in mid September.</P>
      <P>According to the budgets allocated by the Executive Yuan,
government revenue and spending is estimated to amount to NT$1.4
trillion (US$41.25 billion) and NT$1.63 trillion for 2005, up by 3.9
percent and 2.4 percent, respectively, over the 2004 levels.</P>
      <P>The NT$232.9 billion shortfall and old debts worth NT$60 billion
are set to incur a financial gap of NT$292.9 billion for next year,
which will be managed by the government through issuing bonds and
funds.</P>
      <P>Budget appropriated for educational and cultural affairs and
science research amounts to NT$317.7 billion, the lion's share of
19.4 percent of the total and representing a growth of 3.7 percent
year-on-year.</P>
      <P>Expenditure earmarked for social welfare projects reaches
NT$289.1 percent, making up 17.7 percent of the total and marking an
annual increase of 2.6 percent.</P>
      <P>Funds going to economic development plans and national defense
needs stand at NT$257.4 billion and NT$251.9 billion, up by 5.1
percent and 0.5 percent, respectively. The 5.1 growth rate is the
largest increase among all categories.</P>
      <P>The Ministry of National Defense also lists an additional
spending worth NT$21.8 billion as part of a major military
procurement plan that will span 15 years.</P>
      <P>The Executive Yuan estimates that Taiwan's gross national product
will yield NT$11.2 trillion next year, equivalent of a per-capita
income of US$14,463. It forecasts that the country's economic growth
rate for the whole of 2005 will be 4.5 percent, with consumer product
prices rising by a mild 1.6 percent.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0036" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>REPORT ON 3-19 SHOOTING DOES NOT RULE OUT POLITICAL ASSASSINATION</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug. 30 (CNA)
(By Maubo Chang)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>U.S. forensic expert Henry Lee's report on
the March 19 shooting of President Chen Shui-bian does not rule out
political assassination as a possible cause, State Public
Prosecutor-General Lu Ren-fa said Monday.</P>
      <P>At a news conference called hours after he received the report,
Lu disputed news reports made the previous day that Lee does not
think the shooting was an assassination attempt. He noted that Lee
did not suggested any motivation behind the incident, but focused
only on the identification and analysis of the evidence collected at
the scene of the shooting in Tainan.</P>
      <P>Lu said Lee's report confirms that the wound suffered by the
president to his abdomen was caused by a bullet, that it ran from
right to left across the abdomen and that the bullets recovered are
not used by regular handguns.</P>
      <P>Judging by the bullets used in the incident, Lu said, Lee agreed
with the conclusion of the police that a remodeled replica handgun
was used in the incident.</P>
      <P>Although many people question whether such weapons can be lethal,
police records show they have caused at least four fatalities, Lu
said, indirectly denying a claim attributed by newspapers to Lee that
a more powerful weapon would have been used in the shooting if the
shooter was aiming to kill.</P>
      <P>Lu said local investigators assigned to look into the case took
heart from Lee's findings, which generally affirm the direction they
took in their investigation.</P>
      <P>Lu, who will retire Sept. 1, said he was glad to receive the
report one day before he left office. The 130-page English-language
report was delivered by Lee to Taiwan's representative office in New
York Saturday and sent to Taipei via diplomatic pouch.</P>
      <P>Lu said he has asked for a translation of the report, which he
claimed will be helpful in tracking down the shooter, but he added
that the report's contents will not be disclosed before the
investigation ends.</P>
      <P>Lee, who lives in the United States, was asked by the Taipei
authorities to help look into the case. He led four American forensic
experts that examined the shooting scene, and pored over the evidence
they collected at Lee's Connecticut laboratory.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0037" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>EVENT LISTING FOR AUG. 31 IN TAIWAN</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei, Aug. 30 (CNA)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>The following are major events scheduled to
take place Tuesday, Aug. 31:</P>
      <P>10: 00, The Ministry of Foreign Affairs will hold a news
conference at the ministry's headquarters.</P>
      <P>10:30, Vice Premier Yeh Chu-lan will start an inspection tour of
mountainous townships devastated by mudslides in Hsinchu County.</P>
      <P>10:30, A news conference on anti-drug efforts will be held at the
Center for Disease Control.</P>
      <P>11: 30, A joint meeting of exporters and importers associations
around the nation will be held at the Taipei Exporters and Importers
Association.</P>
      <P>12:00, Minister of Justice Chen Ding-nan will deliver a speech at
a meeting of the American Chamber of Commerce to be held at the Far
Eastern Plaza hotel in Taipei.</P>
      <P>13: 30, The ruling Democratic Progressive Party will hold its
Central Standing Committee meeting at the party's headquarters.</P>
      <P>16:00, The Department of Industrial Technology under the Ministry
of Economic Affairs will hold a news conference at the ministry's
headquarters.</P>
      <P>16: 00, The Finance Supervision Commission will hold a news
conference at the commission's headquarters.</P>
      <P>16: 20, The Central Bank of China will hold a news conference at
the bank's headquarters.</P>
      <P>16:30, The Ministry of Finance will hold a news conference at the
ministry's headquarters.</P>
      <P>18: 00, Vice President Annette Lu will attend a business group
meeting at the Cosmos Hotel in Taipei.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0038" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>U.S. CONGRESSIONAL TAIWAN CAUCUS WELCOMES PRESIDENT'S U.S. STOPOVER</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Washington,  Aug. 29 (CNA)
(By Lin Wen-chi and Lilian Wu)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>Four co-chairmen of a pro-Taiwan group
in the U.S. Congress have sent a letter to President Chen Shui-bian
welcoming his transit stops in the United States en route to and from
an upcoming two-nation visit to Central America, a Taiwanese group in
the United States said Sunday.</P>
      <P>Chen will travel to Panama via Hawaii to attend the Sept. 1
inauguration of Panamanian President-elect Martin Torrijos, and will
then visit Belize, another diplomatic ally, to sign a joint
communique with Prime Minister Said Musa before returning to Taiwan
via Seattle Sept. 5.</P>
      <P>The Formosan Association of Public Affairs (FAPA) said in a press
release that the four co-chairmen -- Steve Chabot (R-OH), Dana
Rohrabacher (R-CA), Robert Wexler (D-FL) and Sherrod Brown
(D-OH) -- said in the letter that although Chen will only make
brief stops in the United States, they believe it will help promote
U.S.-Taiwan relations.</P>
      <P>They expressed admiration for Taiwan's political and economic
achievements, saying also that Chen's re-election has demonstrated
the dynamism and solid basis of Taiwan's democracy.</P>
      <P>In the letter, they were also positive about Chen's call for
dialogues with Beijing in his May 20 inauguration speech, and
expressed hope that Beijing will respond positively to Chen's appeal
to establish a cross-Taiwan Strait peace and stability mechanism.</P>
      <P>They said that peace in the Taiwan Strait is crucial to
maintaining peace and stability in East Asia and that Taiwan and the
United States should help and support each other.</P>
      <P>They also welcomed David Ta-wei Lee, the new Republic of China
representative to the United States.</P>
      <P>FAPA officials said that Taiwan-born U.S. Congressman David Wu
(D-OR) also issued a statement saying that he hopes to be able to
meet Chen during his transit stops.</P>
      <P>FAPA President Wu Ming-kee said that Chen's transit stops come at
a time when the Republican Party is holding its national convention
in New York, so that Chen's transit stop will be limited to the West
Coast.</P>
      <P>But he pointed out that the U.S. House of Representatives has
passed two resolutions to request the lifting of the restrictions on
high-ranking Taiwan officials visiting the United States in recent
months.</P>
      <P>FAPA will continue to lobby Congress to lift the restrictions, Wu
added.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0039" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>TAIWAN ECONOMY TO GROW BY 4.5 PERCENT IN 2005: CABINET REPORT</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug.  30 (CNA)
(By Flor Wang)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>As the government expects the country's
economy to continue growing, the Executive Yuan predicts in a report
released Monday that its 2005 economic growth rate will be 4.5
percent, lower than this year's 5.9 percent.</P>
      <P>In its 2005 budget proposal submitted to the Legislative Yuan for
screening in the middle of September, the Executive Yuan forecasts
that Taiwan's gross national product will swell to NT$11.2 trillion
(US$329 billion) next year, up by 4.5 percent compared to the 2004
level.</P>
      <P>The figure will translate into a per-capita income of US$14,463,
reflecting an annual growth of US$538 year-on-year, according to the
Executive Yuan.</P>
      <P>It forecasts that the domestic economy will expand by 4.5 percent
next year, lower than this year's 5.9 percent growth rate, as a
result of a relatively slowed world economy that is estimated to
increase by 3.6 percent for 2005, a level that still outperforms an
2.8 percent average for the last five years.</P>
      <P>Taiwan's economy has been on a rising track since the beginning
of this year, with its exports and imports in the first half of the
year growing by 25.7 percent and 35.6 percent, respectively, over the
previous year's levels, it points out.</P>
      <P>Investment from the private sector will increase by 28.7 percent
for the same period, laying a sound foundation for an economic growth
rate above 5 percent for the whole of 2004, it says.</P>
      <P>Although the international economic expansion is expected to slow
in 2005, the Executive Yuan remains cautiously optimistic about the
economic development at home on the back of Taiwan's competitive and
value-added industries.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0040" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>STRICTER SCREENING TO PREVENT ABSCONDING OF MAINLAND TOURISTS</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug.  30 (CNA)
(By Lilian Wu)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>To prevent any future cases of mainland
Chinese tourists absconding en masse upon arrival in Taiwan, a
verification system will start Wednesday to screen prospective
tourists from the mainland, the Travel Agent Association of the
Republic of China said Monday.</P>
      <P>Hsu Kao-ching, secretary-general of the association, noted that
the Executive Yuan has passed a review report on the control and
management of mainland tourists and will require travel agencies
handling mainland tourist groups to sign a self-disciplinary
agreement.</P>
      <P>The association will also conduct prior telephone verification
according to the information provided by the applicants, and the
applications will be rejected if the information does not match.</P>
      <P>He said that if travel agencies produce fake certificates for
tourists, or if their failure to manage the tourist groups results in
tourists absconding, they will be suspended of their rights for a
period of between one and 12 months, or will be turned over to
related law enforcement agencies.</P>
      <P>He said that the association will require application forms to be
properly filled out, that the contact telephone numbers must be
correct and that the work certificates provided by the tourists'
employers should bear official company stamps.</P>
      <P>If the applicants say they have no relatives or friends in
Taiwan, they will not be able to apply to leave the group while in
Taiwan.</P>
      <P>He said it is hoped through the initial screening of the travel
agencies and the second screening by the association, with final
rechecking by the Immigration Office of the National Police
Administration, the process will become more effective.</P>
      <P>On July 13, 17 mainland tourists ran away en masse upon arriving
in Taiwan, while another group of 13 mainlanders escaped shortly
after arriving at their hotels Aug. 17.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0041" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>POLICE APPEAL FOR INFORMATION ON MAN IN FILM OF MARCH 19 SHOOTING</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug.  30 (CNA)
(By Maubo Chang)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>Police appealed to the public Monday for
information on a man who appears in television footage taken at the
scene seconds before the March 19 shooting of President Chen
Shui-bian took place.</P>
      <P>Coming under new public pressure for a breaking of the case after
the release of a report by a Chinese-American forensic expert, the
police made public again the image of the man caught on camera.</P>
      <P>The man in the film mingled with crowd lining the streets to
welcome Chen during a campaign parade in Tainan. He was dressed in a
white shirt and dark pants, waving a flag of Chen's Democratic
Progressive Party in his right hand and putting his left hand in his
pocket and looking back repeatedly.</P>
      <P>The police said the man appeared in the area where two bullets
were supposed to have been fired that wounded the president and Vice
President Annette Lu, who was by his side in an open-topped jeep.</P>
      <P>Of the 434 persons appearing in the TV footage, 46 are listed by
police as possible shooters. Forty of them have already come forward
to clear their names, with six remaining unaccounted for. Four of the
six can be clearly seen, while the images of the two others are
blurred.</P>
      <P>Police released a photo of the man captured from the television
footage.</P>
      <P>In another development Monday, prosecutors assigned to probe the
case made public a list of the tasks they have completed in probing
the case. The list shows they visited and questioned Scretary General
of the National Security Council Chiou I-jen July 7. Chiou was serving
as the secretary-general to the president when the shooting took
place.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040830.0042" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>PRESIDENT LEAVES FOR CENTRAL AMERICA</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug.  30 (CNA)
(By Maubo Chang)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>President Chen Shui-bian headed for the
Central American states of Panama and Belize for a visit Monday
night.</P>
      <P>In a brief speech before he boarded his plane at the Chiang
Kai-shek International Airport, the president said he delayed and cut
short his trip because of the disaster caused by Typhoon Aere on Aug.
24, saying that although the disaster is of great concern, diplomacy
is also vital for the country and is his task.</P>
      <P>Chen urged his administration to keep working hard to reconstruct
the diaster-affected areas during his overseas trip.</P>
      <P>The president will attend the inauguration of Panamanian
President-elect Martin Torrijos Sept. 1, traveling via Hawaii, and
will continue to Belize Sept. 2.</P>
      <P>He will arrive in Seattle Sept. 3 for an eight-hour stopover on
his way back to Taiwan and will arrive home Sept. 5.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0001" type="multi">
    <HEADLINE>TODAY IN HISTORY</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei, Aug. 31 (CNA)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>Today is Tuesday, Aug. 31, or the 16th
day of the seventh month of the Year of the Monkey according to
the lunar calendar. Following is a list of important events that have
occurred on this date in the past:

12AD: Caligula, originally Gaius Caesar, Roman emperor remembered
for his murderous reign, is born. He succeeded his adopted father
Tiberius. After a severe illness, he displayed the ruthlessness,
extravagance and megalomania that led to his assassination.

1422: Henry V, King of England, who reopened the Hundred Years'
War, defeating the French at Agincourt in 1415 and capturing all of
Normandy by 1419, dies of dysentery in France at the age of 35. His
son Henry VI accedes to the throne at the age of nine months.

1907: The Anglo-Russian Convention is signed in St. Petersburg,
settling differences between the two over Tibet, Afghanistan and
Persia.

1907: Ramon Magsaysay, president of the Philippines from 1953 to
1957, is born.

1939: Adolf Hitler announces the invasion of Poland. Three days
later, both Britain and France declared war on Germany, marking the
outbreak of World War II.

1945: The Nationalist government divides the three northeastern
provinces in Manchuria into nine provinces.

1957: Malaysia achieves independence from Britain with Tengku
Abdul Rahman as its first president.

1961: President Chiang Kai-shek tells 70 visiting American
reporters that Kinmen and Matsu "are as important as West Berlin."

1962: The former British possessions of Trinidad and Tobago
become an independent nation.

1962: The Republic of China recognizes the Republic of Trinidad
and Tobago.

1965: Pakistan and India threaten war over Kashmir.

1968: A strong earthquake rocks northeastern Iran, killing 12,000
people and injuring over 100,000 others.

1974: The first plant to produce high-density polyethylene resins
in the Republic of China is dedicated at Toufen in Miaoli County.

1976: Little League, Big League and Senior League teams return to
Taipei after winning world titles in the United States.

1980: The ROC Mulan soccer team wins the championship at the
first International Women's Soccer Tournament held in the United
States.

1989: Buckingham Palace officially confirms that the marriage of
Queen Elizabeth II's daughter, Anne, and Captain Mark Phillips is on
the rocks.

1990: Premier Hau Pei-tsun advises the Legislative Yuan that ROC
relations with mainland China will operate under the concept of "one
country, two areas."

1992: Former British Prime Minister Margaret Thatcher expresses
support for the ROC's entry into the GATT during her visit to Taipei.

1993: Beijing makes public a white paper reiterating its position
of solving the Taiwan problem by "peaceful reunification" and "one
country, two systems," while refusing to renounce the use of force
against Taiwan.

1994: Russian President Boris Yeltsin and German Chancellor
Helmut Kohl jointly preside over a farewell ceremony marking an end
to half a century of military presence on German soil by troops of
the former Soviet Union.

1994: The IRA declares an unconditional end to its 25-year armed
struggle for a united Ireland and its war against British rule of
Northern Ireland.

1995: The ruling Kuomintang nominates incumbent President Lee
Teng-hui as its presidential candidate.

1997: Britain's Princess Diana and her millionaire companion Dodi
Al Fayed are killed in a Paris car crash.

1999: Raymond F. Burghardt, the newly appointed director of the
Taipei office of the American Institute in Taiwan (AIT), arrives in
Taipei to assume his post.

2000: ROC Minister of National Defense Wu Shih-wen says that the
military will continue to try to obtain an early warning system after
recent war games revealed Taiwan's limited means to counter mainland
Chinese missile attack.

2001: Compaq Computer Inc. and Taiwan's Academia Sinica, the
highest academic researrch institute in Taiwan, sign a cooperative
memorandum to engage in gene and biotechnology research in Taiwan.



Confucius' lesson of the day: "It is only he, in the world, who
possesses absolute truth who can get to the bottom of the law of his
being. He who can get to the bottom of the law of his being will be
able to get to the bottom of the law of being of other men."</TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0002" type="multi">
    <HEADLINE>TAIWAN HEADLINE NEWS</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei, Aug.31 (CNA)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>The lead stories in major Taiwan
dailies on Tuesday are as follows:

The China Times:

President Chen announces cancellation of Han Kuang live-fire
drill after Beijing withdraws troops from Dongshan Island.

The United Daily News:

In a goodwill gesture to Beijing, President Chen cancels
Han Kuang live-fire exercise.

The Liberty Times:

Beijing targets southern Taiwan for its new 'united front'
campaign.

The Taiwan Daily:

Taiwan cancels live-fire drill after Beijing withdraws
troops from Dongshan Island.

The Central Daily News:

Taoyuan County gripped by water shortage.

The China Post:

Presidential Office helps Cabinet block 'Truth Commission.'

The Taiwan News:

Hundreds of thousands protest in New York City.

The Taipei Times:

Respondents favor investigation body.</TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0003" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>TAIWAN CANCELS LIVE AMMO FIRE DRILL TO SHOW ITS SINCERITY: CHEN</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei, Aug. 31 (CNA)
(By P.C.Tang)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>President Chen Shui-bian said early Tuesday
morning that the government has decided to cancel the live ammunition
fire drill of the "Hankuang No. 20" military exercises set for Sept.
9. to show Taiwan's sincerity in pursuing development of cross-strait
cooperation based on the principle of peace.</P>
      <P>The president made the comments aboard his plane heading for an
official visit to two ROC diplomatic allies in Central America
following media reports that mainland China had canceled its annual
military exercise on Dongshan Island.</P>
      <P>Chen will attend the inauguration of Panamanian President-elect
Martin Torrijos Sept. 1 and then visit Belize Sept. 2.</P>
      <P>Taiwan planned to hold an overall combat training drill of ground
and air forces Aug. 25 to cap off the months long "Hankuang No. 20"
military exercises, but the Ministry of National Defense was forced
to postpone the drill due to Typhoon Aere which slammed the island
Aug. 24-25.</P>
      <P>Chen also said he hopes the two sides of the Taiwan Strait can
march toward better cooperation and create a win-win situation.</P>
      <P>Although the president did not confirm whether mainland China had
canceled its military exercise on Dongshan Island while announcing
the government's decision to cancel the live fire drill, he said that
regardless of Beijing's intentions, he has decided to cancel the
drill following consultations Monday evening with Defense Minister
Lee Chieh, who is in favor of the decision.</P>
      <P>Defense Ministry officials confirmed Monday that mainland Chinese
military authorities have recently recalled about 3,000 troops from
Dongshan Island where annual military exercises were originally set
to be held. The officials added that the ministry will continue to
closely monitor the situation.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0004" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>U.S. REPUBLICAN PARTY VOWS TO HELP DEFEND TAIWAN</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>New York,  Aug.  30 (CNA)
(By Lilian Lin and Deborah Kuo)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>The U.S. Republicans adopted a party
platform Monday supporting President George W. Bush's war on global
terrorism and denying mainland China's claimed right to impose its
rule on Taiwan.</P>
      <P>The 93-page platform, approved on the opening day of the
Republican Party's national convention being held at Madison Square
Garden in New York City, made clear that the centerpiece of Bush's
campaign is his war on terror launched after the Sept. 11, 2001,
attacks that killed nearly 3,000 people.</P>
      <P>"Terrorists long ago declared war on America, and now America has
declared war against terrorists, " the platform said. "We are
defending the peace by taking the fight to the enemy."</P>
      <P>The platform criticized mainland China for seeking military
capabilities that could threaten its neighbors, for failing to uphold
its commitments to nuclear non-proliferation, and for violating human
rights.</P>
      <P>Vowing to help defend Taiwan from any move by Beijing to forcibly
unify it with the mainland, the platform indicated that "we deny the
right of Beijing to impose its rule on the free Taiwanese people."</P>
      <P>"All issues regarding Taiwan's future must be resolved peacefully
and must be agreeable to the people of Taiwan," it stressed.</P>
      <P>The platform also vowed to oppose any unilateral change to the
status quo across the Taiwan Strait and to support Taiwan's bid to
join the World Health Organization and other global organizations.</P>
      <P>Meanwhile, a Taiwan delegation of legislators and politicians
from across the political spectrum is attending the Republicans'
national convention as observers.</P>
      <P>Three members of the Taiwan group, namely Liu Shi-fang, a member
of the ruling Democratic Progressive Party's Central Executive
Committee; Legislator Sun Kuo-hua from the opposition Kuomintang; and
Wang Kao-cheng, an academic and stalwart of the opposition People
First Party, were invited to take part in a discussion workshop
sponsored by the International Republican Institute, an important
politics think-tank that is loosely affiliated with the Republican
Party, Monday afternoon.</P>
      <P>Members of the Taiwan delegation are expected to meet important
Republican politicians, members of several key think-tanks and media
leaders in New York in the following days to exchange views on
matters of mutual concern, providing a golden opportunity for Taiwan
to express its opinions and have its voice heard.</P>
      <P>Taiwan's top representative in the United States, David Lee, is
expected to travel from Washington, D.C., to New York Sept. 1 to meet
the Taiwan delegation as well as Taiwan journalists and camera crews
who are in New York to cover the convention.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0005" type="multi">
    <HEADLINE>INTERNATIONAL HEADLINE NEWS</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Los Angeles, Aug.30 (CNA)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>Los Angeles Times: 
Anti-Bush protesters Fill N.Y. Streets.
More than 100,000 demonstrators flooded the
streets of Manhattan in a strong show of oppo-
sition to President Bush and the war in Iraq as
this city geared up for the Republican National
Convention.
(Lu-sheng Chu)</TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0006" type="multi">
    <HEADLINE>INTERNATIONAL HEADLINE NEWS</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Bangkok, Aug.31 (CNA)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>Bangkok Post:Apirak asks PM to help.
Bangkok governor-elect Apirak Kosayodhin is arranging an appointment with
Prime Minister Thaksin Shinawatra to seek the government's cooperation in
implementing his election promises.
(Francis Kuo)</TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0007" type="other">
    <HEADLINE>FOREIGN EXCHANGE RATES</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei, Aug. 31 (CNA)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>The exchange rates* for major foreign
currencies quoted in New Taiwan dollars by Chang Hwa Commercial bank
on Tuesday: 

BUYING RATES     SELLING RATES

US dollar                       33.869          34.269
Euro                            40.61           41.61
Hong Kong dollar                 4.310           4.430
Japanese yen                     0.3069          0.3129
Australian dollar               23.75           23.95
Canadian dollar                 25.75           25.95
Pound sterling                  61.00           61.40
Singapore dollar                19.79           19.99
South African rand               4.98            5.18
Sweden krone                     4.459           4.559
Swiss Franc                     26.56           26.76
Thai baht                        0.8099          0.8299
N. Zealand dollar               22.06           22.26

*  Exchange  rates  for  the  US  dollar  in  amounts  less  than
US$10,000.</TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0008" type="multi">
    <HEADLINE>INTERNATIONAL HEADLINE NEWS</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Manila, Aug. 31 (CNA)
(By Emerson T. Lim)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>Manila Bulletin: Economic team
urges reduction of public debt

The national government's economic managers
submitted to the Senate yesterday the Arroyo
administration's fiscal plan to avert a looming
financial crisis.

The Philippine Daily Inquirer: Economy posts
surprise growth: 6.2% in 2nd quarter

ELECTION spending and increased usage of cellular
phones allowed the Philippine economy to grow by 6.2
percent in the April-June quarter despite the
government's fragile fiscal position, official data
showed Monday.

The Manila Times: '05 budget breaks P1-trillion
mark

MALACANANG is asking Congress to approve a
whopping P1.01 trillion budget for 1995, not just the
P907 billion it announced it had submitted to
Congress, Sen. Ralph Recto said on Monday.</TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0009" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>2 MAINLAND FISHERMEN NABBED FOR SMUGGLING TAIWAN BETEL NUT</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug.  31  (CNA)
(By Lilian Wu)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>Two mainland Chinese fishermen were
arrested for smuggling Taiwan betel nut to mainland China, coast
guard officials on the outlying island of Kinmen reported Tuesday.</P>
      <P>Tipped off recently that underground transactions across the
Taiwan Strait are rampant, the coast guard sent a cutter to step up
patrols over the past days.</P>
      <P>Coast guard officials spotted the mainland Chinese fishing vessel
headed toward mainland China Sunday night after it had received "the
cargo" from a Kinmen fishing vessel.</P>
      <P>The officials intercepted the mainland vessel and found on board
780 kg of betel nut, 80 kg of unripe piper linn fruit and 15 kg of
betel nut leaves of piper linn with a total market value of more than
NT$500,000 (US$14,705).</P>
      <P>The vessel's captain, identified as Wang Jianhua, and fisherman
Wang Jiatai, who both come from Xiamen, Fujian Province, were sent to
the Kinmen Prosecutor's Office for violation of anti-smuggling
regulations and the statute governing the relations between the
people across the Taiwan Strait.</P>
      <P>Wang Jiatai said that he was paid 100 renminbi (about NT$4,110)
for shipping the goods, claiming he risked being arrested because his
family needs the money.</P>
      <P>The Kinmen coast guard intercepted 12,000 kg of betel nut
being smuggled to Kinmen from mainland China in mid-June. But this
time, they seized Taiwan betel nuts.</P>
      <P>Though Taiwan betel nuts are more expensive, they are considered
to be of higher quality and are therefore favored by Taiwan
businesspeople operating on the mainland, the officials said.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0010" type="multi">
    <HEADLINE>INTERNATIONAL HEADLINE NEWS</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Singapore, Aug. 31 (CNA)
(By Charles Kang)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>The Straits
Times:Sengkang to get 3-room HDB flats.

The Lianhe Zaobao:The family has 3 kids to
get priority for ordering HDB flats.</TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0011" type="multi">
    <HEADLINE>INTERNATIONAL  HEADLINE  NEWS</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Tokyo Aug.31 (CNA)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>The Japan Times: Curtain comes down on Athens
Games; Despite attack in marathon, Olympics hailed as success.

In the one major security breach just hours before the Athens Olympic
Games ended Sunday, the leader of the men's marathon was grabbed by
an instruder 5 km from the finish and knocked off the course.</TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0012" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>PFP CHAIRMAN QUESTIONS CANCELLATION OF LIVE-FIRE DRILL</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug.  3 1 (CNA)
(By Deborah Kuo)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>Opposition People First Party (PFP)
Chairman James Soong on Tuesday questioned Taiwan's decision to
cancel a major live-fire drill in response to mainland China's
reported cancellation of its scheduled military exercise on Dongshan
Island.</P>
      <P>Noting that Beijing has not formally announced a cancellation of
the military exercise, Soong said Taiwan cannot afford to
miscalculate nor misjudge the military situation based on incomplete
intelligence.</P>
      <P>President Chen Shui-bian said early Tuesday morning that the
government has decided to cancel the live ammunition war drill of the
"Hankuang 20" military exercises set for Sept. 9. to show Taiwan's
sincerity in pursuing development of cross-strait cooperation based
on the principle of peace.</P>
      <P>Taiwan had planned to hold an overall combat training drill of
ground and air forces Aug. 25 to cap off the months long "Hankuang
No. 20" military exercises, but the Ministry of National Defense was
forced to postpone the drill due to Typhoon Aere which slammed the
island Aug. 24-25.</P>
      <P>Although the president did not confirm whether mainland China had
canceled its military exercise on Dongshan Island while announcing
the government's decision to cancel the live fire drill, he said that
regardless of Beijing's intentions, he has decided to cancel the
drill following consultations Monday evening with Defense Minister
Lee Chieh, who is in favor of the decision.</P>
      <P>Defense Ministry officials confirmed Monday that mainland Chinese
military authorities have recently recalled about 3,000 troops from
Dongshan Island where annual military exercises were originally set
to be held. The officials added that the ministry will continue to
closely monitor the situation.</P>
      <P>Meanwhile, a Beijing official with the State Council's Office of
Taiwan Affairs in charge of public relations declined to confirm
Tuesday whether the combined-services PLA military drills scheduled
to begin around the end of August have been canceled or not.</P>
      <P>Yang Yi, deputy director of the information bureau under the
State Council's Office of Taiwan Affairs, also kept mum when asked by
Taiwan reporters about President Chen Shui-bian's gesture of goodwill
in calling a halt to the final stage of the "Hankuang 20" exercises.</P>
      <P>Yang only said that "you have to look at the situation from a
wider perspective" on the development of cross Taiwan Strait
relations.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0013" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>OPTIMISM SURROUNDS TALKS ON REOPENING TAIWAN-SOUTH KOREA AIR LINKS</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug. 31 (CNA)
(By P.C.Tang)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>Talks between Taipei and Seoul on resuming
long-severed air links between Taiwan and South Korea are progressing
and the public should be cautiously optimistic about the outcome, a
Ministry of Foreign Affairs spokesman said Tuesday.</P>
      <P>Spokesman Lu Ching-lung made the comments while responding to
media questions following reports that negotiations related to the
reestablishment of Taiwan-South Korea air links have entered the
final stage.</P>
      <P>Differences between the two sides have narrowed and Minister of
Foreign Affairs Tan Sun Chen has agreed to several points in
principle and the ministry is optimistic that an announcement could be
forthcoming soon.</P>
      <P>Regular air links between the two countries were stopped 12 years
ago.</P>
      <P>Lu also said that the foreign ministry is cooperating with the
Ministry of Transportation and Communications in the negotiations.</P>
      <P>A new aviation agreement would not only be important for the
economic interests of the two countries, but would positively affect
the relationship between Taiwan and South Korea, Lu maintained. He
declined to elaborate on details of the agreement before a document
is signed.</P>
      <P>Asked whether the ROC government's insistence on sending
ministerial level officials to represent Taiwan to sign an agreement
has been the main factor preventing the two countries from making a
breakthrough on the issue, Lu said that the conclusion of the
negotiations is the most important thing, and who signs an accord is
immaterial as long as both parties agree on the terms.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0014" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>FORMER DPP CHAIRMAN THANKS KMT HEAD FOR REFORM PROPOSALS</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug. 31 (CNA)
(By Deborah Kuo)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>A former chairman of the ruling Democratic
Progressive Party (DPP) , Lin Yi-hsiung, paid a courtesy call on
opposition Kuomintang (KMT) Chairman Lien Chan Tuesday to
congratulate him on the recent passage in the legislature of several
constitutional revisions.</P>
      <P>Lin, who founded a group to campaign for the abolishment of the
Fourth Nuclear Power Plant and for the downsizing of the Legislative
Yuan, said he is glad that by the concerted efforts of the opposition
KMT and the ruling DPP, the legislature passed constitutional
revisions that include reducing the number of seats in the
legislature by about half and changing the legislative electoral
system.</P>
      <P>For his part, Lien said it was the KMT's responsibility as a
major opposition party to see to it that bills on legislative reforms
be passed and promulgated.</P>
      <P>As a matter of fact, Lien said, he began some 20 years ago to
push for a "single seat, two votes" legislative election system and
stressed that the idea is by no means a new one.</P>
      <P>Reducing the number of legislative seats was also agreed upon by
almost all major parties in the country, Lien added.</P>
      <P>Lien also said that all politicians should do a great deal of
soul-searching to examine whether democratization in Taiwan is being
carried out under the principles of fairness and justice.</P>
      <P>Lien said he admired Lin, who has been known in Taiwan as a
"democracy fighter, " and asked Lin to join him someday to work as a
team for the cause of Taiwan's democratization.</P>
      <P>Lin, who has participated in a number of hunger strikes and
sit-ins over the years to champion his ideals, gave Lien a book
written by his daughter, Lin Huan-chun, the only survivor of an
unsolved multiple murder in Lin's residence decades ago. She is now a
mother of three and a musician living in the United States.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0015" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>PRESIDENT CHEN HEADS FOR PANAMA AFTER HECTIC TRANSIT STOP IN HAWAII</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Hawaii,  Aug. 30 (CNA)
(By S. J. Tsai and Sofia Wu)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>President Chen Shui-bian headed for Panama
late Monday after a seven-hour transit stop in Hawaii during which he
met with U.S. politicians, visited Pearl Harbor and attended a dinner
hosted by major Taiwanese associations.</P>
      <P>When the China Airlines plane carrying Chen and his entourage
arrived at Hawaii International Airport at 3: 00 p.m., acting Hawaii
Governor Mark Benneet, acting American Institute in Taiwan (AIT)
Chairman William Brown and ROC Representative to the United States
David Lee boarded the plane to greet Chen.</P>
      <P>Hundreds of Taiwan expatriates turned out to greet Chen when he
and his entourage arrived at the hotel where he was staying. They
waved the U.S. and ROC flags and chanted "A-bian [Chen's nickname]!
Aloha" to welcome the president.</P>
      <P>Senator Daniel K. Inouye paid a courtesy call on Chen at his
hotel. The president also spoke with Brown and Benneet.</P>
      <P>Later on, Chen visited the USS Arizona Memorial Museum at Pearl
Harbor, which is dedicated to commemorating all military personnel
killed in the Pearl Harbor attack in 1941.</P>
      <P>In the evening, Chen attended a dinner hosted by Taiwanese
associations in Hawaii.</P>
      <P>After the dinner, Chen and his entourage left for Panama to
attend the inauguration of Panamanian President-elect Martin Torrijos
Sept. 1.</P>
      <P>Chen is scheduled to travel to Belize Sept. 2 for an official
visit. He will make an eight-hour stopover in Seattle on his way back
to Taiwan on Sept. 5.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0016" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>TAIPEI SHARES PRICES END LOWER</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug. 31 (CNA)
(By Nick Huang)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>Shares prices on the Taiwan Stock Exchange
opened high but closed lower Tuesday, with the weighted index, the
market's key barometer, dropping 23.4 points to close at 5,765.54
points.</P>
      <P>The bourse opened at 5,757.74 and fluctuated between 5,745.33 and
5,864.57 during the day's trading.</P>
      <P>Trading decreased slightly, with 4.5 billion shares changing
hands on a market turnover of NT$100.02 billion (US$2.93 billion).</P>
      <P>Six of the eight major stock categories gained ground, with
textile stocks moving up the most by 3.1 percent, followed by
construction issues by 2.7 percent, paper and pulp issues by 1.9
percent, cement stocks by 1.3 percent, foodstuff issues by 1.2
percent and plastics and chemicals shares by 0.4 percent.</P>
      <P>Two of the major stock categories lost ground, with machinery and
electronics shares moving down by 0.8 percent and banking and
financial shares by 1 percent.</P>
      <P>Losers outnumbered gainers 372 to 304, with 190 stocks remaining
unchanged.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0017" type="multi">
    <HEADLINE>INTERNATIONAL HEADLINE NEWS</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>London, Aug. 31 (CNA)
(By N.K. Han)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>The Times: Foundation hospitals
'strangled by red tape'. 

Foundation hospital chiefs are worried that the
Government's flagship NHS reform programme is being
strangled by bureaucrats and expected changes to the
original vision.

Financial Times: Unions' decline threatens Labour.

Most of Britain's big industrial and private sector unions
have seen their finances badly damaged by the decline of
of their traditional membership bases, analysis by the
Financial Times reveals.</TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0018" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>EDITOR'S NOTE</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>(By N.K. Han)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P> Correction made in CEP 0017 'The Times' headlines: change
'expected' to 'unexpected'

INTERNATIONAL HEADLINE NEWS</P>
      <P>London, Aug. 31 (CNA) The Times: Foundation hospitals
'strangled by red tape'. </P>
      <P>Foundation hospital chiefs are worried that the
Government's flagship NHS reform programme is being
strangled by bureaucrats and unexpected changes to the
original vision. 

Financial Times: Unions' decline threatens Labour.</P>
      <P>Most of Britain's big industrial and private sector unions
have seen their finances badly damaged by the decline of
of their traditional membership bases, analysis by the
Financial Times reveals.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0019" type="multi">
    <HEADLINE>INTERNATIONAL HEADLINE NEWS</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Washington DC,  Aug. 31 (CNA)
(By Jorge Liu)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>The Washington Post: In N.Y., GOP
Hails Its Chief; McCain, Giuliani Open Convention.

Led by former New York mayor Rudolph W. Giuliani and Arizona Sen.
John McCain, Republicans opened their national convention here Monday
night with an invocation of President Bush's leadership after the
terrorist attacks, a powerful defense of his decision to invade Iraq,
and sharp criticism of Democrat John F. Kerry as an indecisive and
unreliable leader.</TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0020" type="multi">
    <HEADLINE>INTERNATIONAL HEADLINE NEWS</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Moscow,  Aug.  31 (CNA)
(By Vlogya Chang)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>The Moscow Times: Official Results Give
Alkhanov 74%.

Kremlin-favored candidate Alu Alkhanov won 74 percent of the vote
in Chechnya's presidential election, election officials said Monday,
amid reports of widespread vote rigging from independent observers.</TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0021" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>U.S. DOLLAR DOWN ON TAIPEI FOREX</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug.  31 (CNA)
(By Elisa Kao)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>The U.S. dollar dropped against the new
Taiwan dollar on the Taipei Foreign Exchange Tuesday, losing NT$0.026
to close at NT$34.053.</P>
      <P>A total of US$409 million changed hands.</P>
      <P>The U.S. currency opened at the high of the day at NT$34.079 and
dropped to the day's low of NT$34.046.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0022" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>PRICES DOWN ON TAIPEI FUTURES MARKET</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug.  31 (CNA)
(By Elisa Kao)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>Prices on Taipei's stock futures market
were lower Tuesday as the Taiwan Stock Exchange (TAIEX)
Capitalization Weighted Index for September dropped 22 points to
close at 5,763, with 52,609 contracts changing hands.</P>
      <P>TAIEX Index futures for October lost 21 points to finish at
5,754, with 409 contracts traded, while December futures moved down
37 points to finish at 5,703, with 29 contracts traded.</P>
      <P>March futures lost 27 points to finish at 5,699, with seven
contracts traded, while June futures moved down 42 points to end at
5,650, with 14 contracts traded.</P>
      <P>No transactions were recorded for other months.</P>
      <P>Taiwan International Mercantile Exchange reference levels for
TAIEX Index futures trading were set Tuesday at 5,785 for September,
5,775 for October, 5,740 for December, 5,726 for March and 5,692 for
June.</P>
      <P>Electronics (TE) and financial (TF) futures, which are sub-index
futures based on Taiwan Stock Exchange-listed electronics shares and
financial stocks, were also lower.</P>
      <P>September TE futures moved down 2.75 points to close at 222.3,
with 6,753 contracts traded, while October TE futures lost 3.1 points
to finish at 221.75, with 91 contracts transacted.</P>
      <P>December TE futures lost 1.1 points to close at 222.5, with two
contracts traded. No transactions were recorded for other months.</P>
      <P>September TF futures lost eight points to finish at 936, with
5,504 contracts changing hands, while October TF futures moved down
5.4 points to end at 929, with 215 contracts traded.</P>
      <P>December TF futures lost 5.8 points to close at 925, with 15
contract transactions, while March TF futures lost three points to
finish at 925, with two contracts traded.</P>
      <P>No transactions were recorded for other months.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0023" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>RED CROSS GETS REPATRIATIONS BACK ON TRACK</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug.  31 (CNA)
(By Lilian Wu)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>Taiwan repatriated 178 illegal mainland
Chinese immigrants Tuesday with the help of the Red Cross after a
hiatus of more than five months.</P>
      <P>The illegals, 95 women (including one baby girl) and 83 men, had
been staying in a detention center on the outlying island of Matsu.</P>
      <P>Hau Lung-bin, secretary-general of the Red Cross Society of the
Republic of China, who was in Matsu to witness the operations along
with his counterpart from the mainland, said he was happy that
cross-strait cooperation helped to bring about the operation.</P>
      <P>Hau noted that mainland China sent its last repatriation ship on
March 12, and that no others were sent because of inclement weather
and the fact that the ship used for the purpose was undergoing annual
maintenance.</P>
      <P>As a result, detention centers in Matsu as well as in Taiwan
proper have become overwhelmed with around 2,800 Chinese illegals,
far surpassed the capacity of the facilities.</P>
      <P>Hau said Minister of the Interior Su Jia-chyuan had asked the Red
Cross Society for help.</P>
      <P>Based on humanitarian concerns, he said the Red Cross Society
contacted its mainland counterpart two months ago to request
assistance in helping resume repatriations and was happy to learn
last week that Beijing has agreed.</P>
      <P>He expressed the hope that both sides can resume three
repatriation trips every two months, and that the trips could take
place more frequent before the Mid-Autumn Festival, a traditional
family reunion day for Chinese that falls on Sept. 28 this year.</P>
      <P>"This will allow the illegals to reunite with their families, and
also ease the burden on the detention centers, " Hau said.</P>
      <P>Fifty-two people are still being held in Matsu after Tuesday's
repatriation, but there are more than 2,000 still detained in
Taiwan as a whole.</P>
      <P>Meanwhile, mainland China also sent back to Taiwan five wanted
Taiwan criminals -- drug convicts Ke Chin-kun and Chen Hsi-Chung;
blackmail convict Hsu Tze-hsin; and gangsters Hsieh Kuo-tung and Han
Chi-kai -- and Lu Yu-chuang who entered mainland China illegally.</P>
      <P>The six were brought back to Taipei after initial questioning by
police in Matsu.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0024" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>CANCELLATION OF LIVE-FIRE DRILL HELPFUL TO CROSS-STRAIT TIES: MND</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug.  31 (CNA)
(By Y.F. Low)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>The government's decision to cancel the
"Hankuang No. 20" live-fire military exercises will help reduce
cross-Taiwan Strait tensions, Ministry of National Defense officials
said Tuesday.</P>
      <P>President Chen Shui-bian confirmed earlier that the drill
originally set for Sept. 9 would be canceled to show Taiwan's
sincerity in pursuing cross-strait peace and cooperation.</P>
      <P>The decision came after mainland China recalled about 3,000
troops from Dongshan Island where annual military exercises were
originally set to be held.</P>
      <P>ROC Minister of National Defense Lee Jye said Taiwan's decision
is reciprocal because Beijing's move may have been a goodwill
gesture.</P>
      <P>Lee, meanwhile, said the "Tung Hsin 16" training drill for
reservists and the "Wan An 27" civil defense drill will be held as
planned in September.</P>
      <P>The annual "Tung Hsin" training exercise was originally scheduled
for July, but was postponed to September due to the extensive
devastation to central mountainous regions caused by Typhoon Mindulle
in early July.</P>
      <P>In addition to testing the reserve forces' mobilization and
tactical combat prowess, the joint exercises will also include
homeland security protection measures such as anti-terrorist
operations.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0025" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>OPPOSITION FAVORS FORMER JUDICIAL YUAN HEAD AS COMMISSION  CHAIR</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug.  31 (CNA)
(By Y.F. Low)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>The opposition is planning to designate
former Judicial Yuan president Shih Chi-yang to chair their "truth
investigation commission" for the March 19 shooting of President Chen
Shui-bian and Vice President Annette Lu, reliable sources said
Tuesday.</P>
      <P>The opposition "pan-blue alliance" of the Kuomintang (KMT) and
People First Party (PFP) , which holds a small majority in the
Legislative Yuan, pushed through a special statute last week to make
possible the commission's formation.</P>
      <P>According to the law, the commission will be made up of 17
professionals recommended by various political parties, including
five by the KMT and four by the PFP.</P>
      <P>A chairman will be elected from among the commission members.</P>
      <P>The sources said the KMT has already decided on its choices,
including Shih, former State Public Prosecutor-General Chen Han,
lawyer Wang Ching-feng, coroner Yang Jih-sung and the another
identified only by his surname, Huang.</P>
      <P>The KMT believes Shih's credentials and professional background
will make him the best candidate for the chairmanship and is
confident he will win the PFP's endorsement, the sources said.</P>
      <P>The Executive Yuan is expected to request the legislature to
reconsider the bill, calling the commission unconstitutional. But it
is uncertain as to whether the bill will be overruled in view of the
dominance enjoyed by the opposition.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0026" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>TAIWAN MISSION TO VISIT RUSSIA TO BOLSTER  TRADE</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei, Aug. 31 (CNA)
(By Deborah Kuo)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>A Taiwan mission is scheduled to depart for
Russia Sept. 5 to bolster Taiwan-Russia ties in business, trade, the
sciences and humanitarian aid, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs (MOFA)
reported Tuesday.</P>
      <P>The 42-member Taiwan mission, to be headed by Wu Rong-i,
president of the Taiwan Institute of Economic Research and vice
chairman of the Taiwan-Russia Association, is scheduled to visit
Russia Sept. 5-13, said Tseng Ching-yuan, director-general of the
MOFA's Department of West Asian Affairs.</P>
      <P>Topping the mission's itinerary is attending the second
Taiwan-Russia Cooperation Forum for discussions on loans for small-
and medium-sized enterprises as well as development of science-based
industrial parks, according to Tseng.</P>
      <P>During their eight-day stay, the Taiwan group will meet
representatives from Russia's business and trade sectors for a series
of talks.</P>
      <P>Tseng said that there will be a contract signing ceremony,
featuring contracts for orders worth over US$100 million to be placed
by Taiwan businesses for Russian goods.</P>
      <P>In addition, he said, Wu and his group members will sign an
agreement with the Russian Ministry of Health and Social Development
on Taiwan's donation of US$200,000 for the purchase of convertible
X-ray inspection equipment to be used in the Altai Krai territory
located in the remote area bordering Russia, Mongolia, China and
Kazakhstan.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0027" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>AGRICULTURE COUNCIL TO LAUNCH DRIVE AGAINST SMUGGLED MAINLAND GOODS</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei, Aug. 31 (CNA)
(By Flor Wang)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>The Cabinet-level Council of Agriculture is
planning a drive to build public awareness against illegal
agricultural products smuggled in from mainland China, a council
spokesman said Tuesday.</P>
      <P>The council will launch the intensive campaign through a variety
of mass media outlets, including TV, newspapers, radio, magazines,
web sites and bus ads. They will focus on promoting Taiwan consumers'
awareness against illegal agricultural products from the mainland,
the spokesman said.</P>
      <P>The council will introduce effective methods to help the public
distinguish differences between domestic and mainland farm produce as
part of its efforts to secure food safety for local consumers in view
of rampant smuggled mainland agricultural goods in the home market,
he said.</P>
      <P>In addition to the publicity campaign, he said that government
authorities have also stepped up efforts to block contraband goods
coming from the mainland.</P>
      <P>During the first seven months of this year, the government
destroyed as much as 972 metric tons of smuggled agricultural and
poultry products, such as peanuts, rice, small red beans, dry
mushrooms, garlic, betel nuts, tea and fruits.</P>
      <P>In a bid to wipe out false product origin certificates issued by
other countries, the council has also asked relevant government
agencies to strengthen their scrutiny of such documents and import
contracts, he noted.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0028" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>U.S. WELCOMES TAIWAN CANCELLATION OF LIVE-FIRE MILITARY DRILL: AIT</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Hawaii, Aug. 30 (CNA)
(By S. J. Tsai and Sofia Wu)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>The United States has welcomed and
recognizes Taiwan's decision to cancel its planned "Hankuang No. 20"
live-fire military drill to signify its resolve to promote peace and
stability in the Taiwan Strait, the acting chairman of the American
Institute in Taiwan (AIT) said Monday.</P>
      <P>William Brown made the remarks after President Chen Shui-bian
announced aboard a flight from Taipei to Hawaii earlier in the day
that Taiwan's armed forces have decided to cancel the live-fire
military exercise scheduled for Sept. 9 -- the finale of the
months-long "Hankuang" series of combined-services training drills.</P>
      <P>Brown traveled to Hawaii from the U.S. mainland to greet Chen who
made a seven-hour transit stop en route to Panama to attend the
inauguration of Panamanian President-elect Martin Torrijos Sept. 1.</P>
      <P>The acting top U.S. liaison officer with Taiwan in the absence of
formal diplomatic ties between the two countries said the U.S.
government welcomes Taiwan's decision to cancel its planned military
exercise as a goodwill gesture to mainland China.</P>
      <P>Prior to Chen's departure for Hawaii for a hectic transit stop en
route to Panama, the Ministry of National Defense (MND) confirmed
that mainland China has withdrawn about 3,000 ground troops from
Dongshan Island, prompting speculation that Beijing may have canceled
plans for further war games there.</P>
      <P>Dongshan Island, which lies opposite Taiwan, was the scene of a
major mainland military drill in May, when 18,000 troops from the
People's Liberation Army simulated an invasion of Taiwan.</P>
      <P>MND spokesman Maj. Gen. Huang Suey-sheng said more than 3,000
ground troops moved to Dongshan in mid-August had since been
gradually pulled out.</P>
      <P>"Given the development, the likelihood of a drill is quite low
but we will continue to watch the situation," Huang said.</P>
      <P>Chen told reporters during the flight from Taiwan to Hawaii that
no matter whether Beijing has really canceled its military
maneuvering plan, he is determined to cancel the "Hankuang" live-fire
drill after consultations with Minister of National Defense Li Jye,
who Chen said was in favor of the cancellation.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0029" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>CRACKDOWN ON GRAFT AND TEXTBOOK PIRACY TOP PRIORITY: JUSTICE MINISTER</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug.  31 (CNA)
(By Lilian Wu)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>Minister of Justice Chen Ding-nan said
Tuesday that his ministry will dedicate itself to ending graft and
protecting intellectual property rights for textbooks in the next two
years.</P>
      <P>Chen made the promise when he was invited to address a luncheon
sponsored by the American Chamber of Commerce in Taipei and the
European Council of Commerce and Trade.</P>
      <P>Over the past four years, Chen said, the ministry's task of
cracking down on organized crime and bribery has been successful and
the next step will focus on graft and piracy.</P>
      <P>"This is because the ruling Democratic Progressive Party has
promised those in Taiwan, especially foreigners, that it will create
an environment suitable for investment," he said.</P>
      <P>He also said his ministry aims to "lower Taiwan's piracy rate to
the level of advanced nations, about 30 percent."</P>
      <P>He said colleges and universities will start their new school
year soon and the top law enforcer said that the ministry wants to
achieve good results in its crackdown on textbook piracy.</P>
      <P>Chen noted that the ministry conducts raids on copying shops near
school campus every September when a new school year begins, and
these have been successful, although the ministry has also noticed
that pirating has moved on-campus.</P>
      <P>"The ministry will work with the Ministry of Education on how to
enter school campuses to effectively enforce the law," Chen said.</P>
      <P>Although the law does not stipulate which places are off-limits
for law enforcers to search, authorities will handle the situation
with tact when entering such places as school campuses, the
Legislative Yuan or military barracks to avoid controversy, Chen
said.</P>
      <P>Chen said that the protection of intellectual property rights
(IPR) has been one of his top priorities since he assumed his post
four years ago. With the world becoming centered on a knowledge-based
economy, if a government cannot effectively protect IPR, then
enterprises and individuals will have no interest in investing in
research and development, a situation he said will seriously affect a
nation's development and creativity.</P>
      <P>As to whether local students can afford the steep prices of
foreign textbooks, Chen said that bookshops should be able to cut
their prices.</P>
      <P>He said that all intellectual property has its own particular
knock-off market. In addition to textbook piracy, the marketing of
fake medicines is very serious; still worse, most fake medicines are
sold through professional pharmacies, doing much harm to the public.
For this reason, the ministry organized a concerted crackdown on
pharmacies across the island in July 2004 and called on pharmacists
to refuse to sell medicines with unidentified origins.</P>
      <P>He also talked about the most formidable challenge that comes
from Internet piracy, but he said that the new revised copyright law
has been approved by a provisional session of the Legislative Yuan,
addressing concerns about criminal penalties and protection of high
technology.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0030" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>TAIWAN DONATES RICE TO MONGOLIA</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug.  31 (CNA)
(By Sofia Wu)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>Taiwan will donate 120 tons of rice to
Mongolia, which is facing a food shortage, the Ministry of Foreign
Affairs (MOFA) said Tuesday.</P>
      <P>Tseng Ching-yuan, director of the MOFA's West Asian Affairs
Department, said the first shipment of 100 tons will be shipped Sept.
10 and is scheduled to arrive in Mongolia in early October.</P>
      <P>The World Vision charity's Mongolia chapter will be responsible
for distributing the rice, Tseng said.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0031" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>63 PERCENT OF CHILDREN HAVE BEEN BULLIED AT SCHOOL: POLL</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug.  31 (CNA)
(By Y.F. Low)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>Sixty-three percent of elementary school
students have been bullied at schools while 66 percent are aware of
school bullies, according to the results of a survey released
Tuesday.</P>
      <P>The survey was conducted by the Child Welfare League Foundation
(CWLF) among 460 elementary school children.</P>
      <P>CWLF officials said they have received nearly 100 complaints
about children being bullied at school since the recent launch of a
children's hotline.</P>
      <P>A number of parents and teachers have also complained that their
children have refused to go to school over fear of being bullied.</P>
      <P>The survey found that more than 50 percent of the respondents
have occasionally been bullied, while nearly 10 percent said they are
bullied constantly.</P>
      <P>Only 36 percent of the respondents said they have never been
bullied.</P>
      <P>In more than 50 percent of bullying cases, the children were
bullied verbally, the survey shows, while 36 percent suffered
physical bullying and 27 percent were bullied by being ostracized.</P>
      <P>When bullied, 41 percent of the respondents said they simply
endured it, 33 percent said they tell their parents, 28 percent said
they tell their teachers and 10 percent said they take retaliatory
action.</P>
      <P>Less than 10 percent of those surveyed said they would take the
initiative to help a bullied schoolmate, according to the poll.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0032" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>TEXAS REPUBLICANS CALL FOR RECOGNITION OF TAIWAN</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Washington,  Aug. 31 (CNA)
(By Jorge Liu and Elisa Kao)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>The Texas Republican Party has called
for the recognition of Taiwan as a sovereign and independent country
in its party platform and has urged the U.S. Congress to pass a
Taiwan Security Enhancement Act to help defend Taiwan.</P>
      <P>The Republican Party passed its platform Aug. 30 during a
national convention held in New York, in which it stressed that
Beijing has no rights to coercively impose its reign on Taiwan.</P>
      <P>The platform, which was approved, also states that problems
related to Taiwan's future should be resolved peacefully by measures
agreed by the Taiwan people, and that if the mainland violates these
principles, the United States will react accordingly, including
helping Taiwan defend itself.</P>
      <P>The platform of the Texas Republican Party has more say on
cross-Taiwan Strait ties and strongly recommends the removal of
Permanent Normal Trade Relations (formerly Most Favored Nation
status) with the mainland unless five conditions are met: A formal
peace treaty between North and South Korea; a significant improvement
in mainland government policies on human rights; religious freedom on
the mainland; a halt to Beijing's aggressive behavior toward its
neighbors, particularly Taiwan; and a halt to transfers of nuclear,
biological and chemical technology to Iran, Pakistan and North Korea.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0033" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>TAIWAN COMPETITIVE IN PUBLIC WLAN MARKET</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug. 31 (CNA)
(By Flor Wang)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>Taiwan is expected to play a leading role
in the global public wireless local area networking (WLAN) market
thanks to its strong manufacturing clout and full government support,
an industry expert said Tuesday.</P>
      <P>Wu Chen-sheng, general manager of the Nortel Network in Taiwan,
made the analysis while giving a keynote speech at an international
seminar on the prospects for the wireless telecommunications
industry.</P>
      <P>Citing research statistics, Wu reported that the country's
telecommunications industry ranks as the world's 6th most competitive
on the back of various key factors that place Taiwan in ninth spot
globally in terms of digital penetration index and in second spot in
terms of the fast-growing telecommunications volume.</P>
      <P>In addition, Wu said, Taiwan enjoys the world's No. 1 cellular
phone ownership rate of 113 percent and the world's fourth highest
broadband penetration rate of 9.4 percent.</P>
      <P>All these facts are proof that Taiwan is a major market for
worldwide telecommunications businesses and that the country
possesses an indispensable importance in WLAN product manufacturing,
as the 91 percent of the world's WLAN goods are made in Taiwan, he
added.</P>
      <P>He also cited all-out government backing as another significant
driving force behind the promising domestic industry.</P>
      <P>The "M-Taiwan" project and the plan of "10 mobile cities plus 15
special mobile districts" around Taiwan by 2008 being put into
practice by the Science and Technology Advisory Group to the
Executive Yuan will create a mobile "ubiquitous network" throughout
the country to provide people with easy access to the Internet
through WLAN and their mobile phones anywhere in Taiwan, he said.</P>
      <P>The aim of the "Mobile Taiwan" project is to set up the basic
infrastructure to combine cellular phone network service, IT computer
platforms, and broadband Internet links, Kao Tien-tzu, head of
telecommunication and information section at the advisory group, was
quoted as saying.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0034" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>DOH HEAD HOPES TAIWAN CAN MASS PRODUCE FLU VACCINE IN 2 TO 3 YEARS</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug. 31 (CNA)
(By Lilian Wu)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>The nation's top health official expressed
hope Tuesday that Taiwan can start to mass produce influenza vaccines
within two or three years.</P>
      <P>Department of Health Minister Chen Chien-jen said it is
immaterial whether the vaccines will be produced by domestic
manufacturers or by joint ventures with foreign manufacturers, as
long as the vaccines are produced quickly.</P>
      <P>Chen's remarks came at a time when the World Health Organization
estimates that there will a major outbreak of influenza in the world
within five years.</P>
      <P>Chen expressed hope that a special law can be enacted to ensure
the survival of domestic vaccine production manufacturers on one
hand, but that will also put a restriction on exports, meaning that
the vaccines will have to first satisfy the needs of Taiwan before
they can be exported to other countries.</P>
      <P>"It is a major challenge for Taiwan to guard against the outbreak
of influenza," Chen said.</P>
      <P>He said that medical literature shows that mainland China's
Fujian and Guangdong provinces, two of the provinces located nearest
Taiwan opposite Taiwan Strait, are often the sources of new strains
of influenza.</P>
      <P>Noting that more than 15,000 Taiwan people shuttle across the
Taiwan Strait every day, he said that in case of an outbreak on the
mainland, Taiwan would bear the brunt of the dire consequences and
"for the sake of our own and the world's health, Taiwan will have to
contain the disease."</P>
      <P>Chen also said that under a "fighting the flu outbreak" project,
the DOH will propose a budget of NT$10 billion (US$294.11 million)
over the next five years.</P>
      <P>The project will include the storage of vaccine -- which only
remains viable for five years -- for 10 percent of the nation's 23
million people.</P>
      <P>The amount is calculated based on the consideration that not
everyone on the island will contract influenza in the event of an
outbreak, while economics, age group structure and population
concentrations will also be taken into account.</P>
      <P>The Department of Health (DOH) will also strengthen the screening
of passengers with fever at ports and airports, and will test each
individual case within the shortest period of time to learn which
strain of virus they are infected with.</P>
      <P>The DOH will also step up communications with legislators on the
prevention of communicable diseases in the hope that the legislature
will pass the relevant legislation in the next session.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0035" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>DEFENSE CHIEF MAKES CASE FOR MILITARY BUILD-UP</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei, Aug. 31 (CNA)
(By Maubo Chang)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>Minister of National Defense Lee Jye made a
case for military build-up Tuesday, claiming that the country will
rue the day if it fails to do so.</P>
      <P>At a lunch party hosted for local journalists on the eve of
Journalist's Day, Lee made an appeal for public support for his
ministry's request for a NT$610.8 billion (US$18.23 billion) arms
purchase from the United States.</P>
      <P>He said mainland China is taking a two-pronged approach toward
Taiwan -- suffocating the country diplomatically while strengthening
its military in an attempt to gain air, sea and missile superiority
over Taiwan.</P>
      <P>Although there is no military conflict across the Taiwan Strait
for the time being, Lee said, Beijing has undertaken non-military
warfare against Taiwan in the fields of propaganda and public opinion
in order to break down the Taiwan people's willingness to stand
against Beijing.</P>
      <P>Beijing is also aggressively seeking an excuse to justify an
attack on Taiwan, to preempt international interference, Lee claimed.</P>
      <P>He claimed that his ministry's plan to acquire PAC-3 Patriot
missiles, diesel-electric submarines and anti-submarine aircraft, is
meant to close holes in the country's security net. The plan, he
said, was formulated to meet the country's military needs and does
not involve politics.</P>
      <P>The price for the arms purchase could be cut by NT$100 billion if
domestic shipbuilders give up their attempts to take part in the
building of the eight submarines, Lee went on.</P>
      <P>Furthermore, the cost -- to be financed with a special budget
over 15 years -- will work out at about NT$33 billion per year,
which, combined with the defense ministry's regular budget of NT$264
billion in 2004, will account for 2.85 percent of the country's gross
domestic product for that year, he said.</P>
      <P>That is relatively low compared to 8 percent for Israel, 4.73
percent for Singapore and 4 percent for the United States, and will
not divert the country's regular budget, Lee claimed.</P>
      <P>The security of the nation is priceless and the Patriot missiles
will boost the people's confidence in the country's security, while
submarines and anti-submarine aircraft will be valuable deterrents,
according to Lee.</P>
      <P>The ministry's request is pending approval by the Legislative
Yuan. Critics of the arms purchase plan claim it will drain the
country's wealth and increase the arms race between Taiwan and the
mainland, which Taiwan cannot afford.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0036" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>MAINLAND CHINESE FIGHTER SORTIES AFFECT TAIWAN'S EARLY-WARNING TIME</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug. 31 (CNA)
(By Lilian Wu)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>Mainland Chinese fighters make nearly 100
sorties on average per month, which adversely affects the
early-warning time for Taiwan, according to a 2004 report on the
mainland's military might released Tuesday by the Ministry of
National Defense (MND).</P>
      <P>The MND made the report in its annual report to the Legislative
Yuan in the hope of convincing the legislators that a proposed
NT$610.8 billion (US$18.23 billion) arms purchase from the United
States now pending in the legislature is necessary to help deter the
mainland threat.</P>
      <P>The report said that the mainland has greatly improved its
economy in recent years and that it has spent a lot in the research,
development and purchase of state-of-the-art weaponry recently,
including the Sukhoi-series of fighters and Kilo-class submarines.</P>
      <P>The report said the mainland has in recent years continued to
conduct combined forces exercises and that its naval and fishing
vessels have continued to expand their areas of operation.</P>
      <P>The nearly 100 air sorties per month are part of the mainland's
attempts to shorten Taiwan's warning time and as there is no military
mutual trust mechanism between the two sides of the Taiwan Strait,
the report said, a confrontation could easily be triggered due to
miscalculation.</P>
      <P>But the MND also pointed out that the mainland is currently
focusing on its economic development and raising the country's
profile, for which it needs a stable environment.</P>
      <P>The report says that Beijing will continue its verbal attacks and
military intimidation and upgrade its military, but the MND estimates
that it will refrain from using force against Taiwan for the time
being, as long as there is no provocation and as long as Taiwan
maintains a military balance with the other side of the strait.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0037" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>PRESIDENT COULD BE QUESTIONED OVER SHOOTING</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug.  31 (CNA)
(By Y.F. Low)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>Members of a Control Yuan investigative
panel said Tuesday they might request the testimony of President Chen
Shui-bian to assist their investigation into the administrative
responsibilities over the March 19 shooting of Chen and Vice
President Annette Lu.</P>
      <P>The panel set up by the watchdog body is made up of Chao Ron-yaw,
Chern Jinn-lih and Huang Wu-tzu and is in charge of probing the
negligence of security officials concerned, as well as the activation
of the "national security mechanism" in the wake of the shooting.</P>
      <P>After questioning former and incumbent National Security Council
secretaries-general Kang Ning-hsiang and Chiou I-jen, the panel is
planning to request Premier Yu Shyi-kun, who chaired the national
security contingency meeting, to testify on the process of activating
the mechanism, the members said.</P>
      <P>The opposition "pan-blue alliance" of the Kuomintang and People
First Party has claimed that the activation of the national security
mechanism was one of the reasons leading to their narrow defeat in
the presidential election.</P>
      <P>According to the alliance, many military servicemen and police
officers, most of whom the alliance claims are pan-blue supporters,
were unable to vote in the March 20 presidential election because of
the mechanism's activation.</P>
      <P>It also claims the shooting was set up by the ruling Democratic
Progressive Party to give it an advantage in the election.</P>
      <P>The Control Yuan July 6 impeached eight sitting and former
security officials for their slow and sloppy response to the
election-eve shooting.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0038" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>JAPAN REMOVES BAN ON POULTRY IMPORTS FROM TAIWAN: BOFT</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug.  31 (CNA)
(By Flor Wang)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>Japan has removed its ban on poultry
imports from Taiwan, so that poultry produced or raised after June 11
is permitted to enter the Japanese market, a spokesman for the Bureau
of Foreign Trade (BOFT) said Tuesday.</P>
      <P>According to the BOFT official, the Japanese government made the
decision a day earlier after inspection officials sent to Taiwan in
early July found that local poultry farms have made full preparations
and have imposed controls against any new breakout of bird flu.</P>
      <P>Japan imposed the ban Jan. 16, shortly after officials of the
Bureau of Animal and Plant Health Inspection and Quarantine under the
Council of Agriculture (COA) discovered the H5N2 bird flu virus for
the first time on a poultry farm in central Changhua County earlier
the same month.</P>
      <P>The Cabinet-level COA applied to have the Japanese ban lifted
June 11 after a 90-day period had passed without any fresh bird flu
cases.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0039" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>TAIWAN PLANS TO RECRUIT OVERSEAS MAINLAND CHINESE TALENT</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug.  31 (CNA)
(By Elisa Kao)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>Taiwan plans to recruit mainland Chinese
high-tech experts living abroad in view of a domestic shortage of
high-tech manpower, a Council for Economic Planning and Development
(CEPD) official said Tuesday.</P>
      <P>CEPD Vice Chairman Thomas M.F. Yeh noted that according to
statistics, there will be a need for 1,585 experts with doctorates
and 23,193 experts with masters degrees in the next three years,
while the current educational system can only supply 1,140 doctorates
and 18,579 masters holders in the period.</P>
      <P>To overcome the shortfall, the Ministry of Economic Affairs
(MOEA) has suggested the introduction of foreign talent, including
Indian software experts and overseas mainland Chinese high-tech
workers, in addition to the enhancement of high level education and
technical training education.</P>
      <P>As there are still limitations on the introduction of mainland
experts to Taiwan, Chinese professionals living abroad will be the
first target in the recruitment plan, a CEPD official said.</P>
      <P>Yeh stressed that the high-tech talent recruitment program will
not affect the future of domestic experts, as the plan will be a
short-term measure and the government will continue strengthening the
education and training of domestic experts.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0040" type="multi">
    <HEADLINE>INTERNATIONAL HEADLINE NEWS</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>New York,  Aug. 31 (CNA)
(By Lillian Lin)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>New York Times: Procession of speakers
invoke Bush's leadership after 9/11.

The Republican Party opened its convention Monday with a searing
evocation of the Sept. 11 attacks that leveled the World Trade Center
three years ago, as former Mayor Rudolph W. Giuliani of New York
asserted that Senator John Kerry did not have the fortitude to lead
the nation through a war on terror. A procession of speakers invoked
President Bush's leadership after Sept. 11, 2001.

Wall Street Journal: How stem cells became hurdle for GOP
campaign.

Three years ago, President Bush used his first televised
presidential address to put the emotional issue of embryonic
stem-cell research behind him. As Republicans gather in the New York
convention, the stem-cell controversy has grown more divisive. A
number of conservative Republican Party stalwarts, including Sens.
Trent Lott and Orrin Hatch, have joined Nancy Reagan and party
moderates in breaking with the president on the issue. The stem-cell
debate shows the power of promising new technology to scramble
American politics. The White House has discovered that the yearning
for a cure to debilitating diseases doesn't divide along party lines,
nor does the new and agonizing moral debate about what constitutes
life.</TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0041" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>BAD LOAN RATIO DOWN FURTHER IN JULY</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug.  31 (CNA)
(By Flor Wang)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>Taiwan banks made further progress in
improving their performance in July, with the average bad loan ratio
lowered to 3.53 percent as of the end of the month, a 0.01 percent
drop from the June level, a Financial Supervision Commission
spokesman reported Tuesday.</P>
      <P>The July average also marks a 0.8 percent decrease against the
figure posted at the end of December last year, the spokesman said,
adding that Taiwan banks had incurred bad loans worth NT$536.5
billion (US$15.8 billion) as of the end of last month.</P>
      <P>During the period from January 1999 to July 2004, the banks wrote
off bad loans totaling NT$1.289 trillion, 11.79 percent of which was
generated by benefits as a result of cuts in corporate taxes and
increased reserve funds, according to the spokesman. The remaining
88.21 percent of the bad loans were diminished by the banks with
their own business earnings.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0042" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>ROC PRESIDENT VOWS TO PURSUE CROSS-STRAIT PEACE</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Hawaii,  Aug. 30 (CNA)
(By S.J. Tsai and Sofia Wu)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>Republic of China President Chen Shui-bian
said Monday he will lead the people of Taiwan to "pursue peace across
the Taiwan Strait and around the world."</P>
      <P>Since the people on both sides of the Taiwan Strait speak a
common language and have common ethnic origins, Chen said, they have
no reason to continue their hostility toward each other.</P>
      <P>"The two sides of the Taiwan Strait should learn from the
experience of the United States and Japan, who were enemies during
World War II but who have become best friends and working partners, "
Chen said.</P>
      <P>Chen, who arrived in Hawaii at 3 p.m. Monday for a seven-hour
transit stop en route to Panama to attend the Sept. 1 inauguration of
Panamanian President-elect Martin Torrijos, made the remarks at a
dinner hosted by Taiwanese associations in Hawaii in his honor.</P>
      <P>"While touring the USS Arizona Memorial Museum at Pearl Harbor
earlier in the day, I had deep feelings for those who sacrificed
their lives in war. I firmly believe that peace is the most precious
value. Let's say `no' to war. My ultimate life goal is to lead the 23
million Taiwan people to pursue cross-strait peace and to safeguard
world peace," Chen said.</P>
      <P>After Beijing canceled a planned late-August military exercise on
Dongshan Island, Chen said he announced aboard the flight from Taipei
to Hawaii the cancellation of Taiwan's Hankuang 20 live-fire training
drill originally scheduled for Sept. 9 as show of goodwill toward
Beijing.</P>
      <P>"Regardless of Beijing's intentions, I'm determined to cancel the
Hankuang live-fire drill after consultations with Minister of
National Defense Lee Jye, who was in favor of my decision, " Chen
said.</P>
      <P>When the China Airlines plane carrying Chen and his entourage
arrived at Hawaii International Airport, acting Hawaii Governor Mark
Bennett, acting American Institute in Taiwan (AIT) Chairman William
Brown and Republic of China Representative to the United States David
Lee boarded the plane to greet him.</P>
      <P>Hundreds of Taiwan expatriates also turned out to greet Chen when
he and his entourage arrived at his hotel. They waved U.S.
and ROC flags and chanted "A-bian (Chen's nickname)! Aloha" to
welcome the president.</P>
      <P>Senator Daniel K. Inouye paid a courtesy call on Chen at his
hotel and the president also spoke with Brown and Bennett.</P>
      <P>Later, Chen visited the USS Arizona Memorial Museum, which
commemorates the military personnel killed in the attack on Pearl
Harbor by the Japanese in 1941.</P>
      <P>He also toured the battleship USS Missouri, where Japan signed
the Instrument of Surrender Sept. 2, 1945 that marked the end of
World War II.</P>
      <P>Saying that Hawaii can bear witness to the ROC's existence as a
sovereign state, Chen noted Hsu Yung-chang represented the ROC at the
Instrument of Surrender signing ceremony in 1945.</P>
      <P>Chen said he hopes the world can respect and recognize the ROC's
continued existence as a sovereign state since 1911. He added that he
is the ROC's 11th-term president.</P>
      <P>After the dinner, Chen and his entourage left for Panama, after
which he is scheduled to travel to Belize Sept. 2 for an official
visit. He will make an eight-hour stopover in Seattle on his way back
to Taiwan Sept. 5.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0043" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>INTERIOR MINISTRY TO HELP FOREIGN BRIDES WITH LIFE IN TAIWAN</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug.  31 (CNA)
(By Elisa Kao)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>The Ministry of the Interior (MOI) will
cooperate with other countries in setting up a consulting mechanism
to help foreign and mainland Chinese brides integrate into local
society, a MOI official said Tuesday.</P>
      <P>The official made the remark in a meeting on ways to take care of
the foreign brides, with the participation of officials from the
Ministry of Foreign Affairs, the Ministry of Education, the Council
for Cultural Affairs, local city and county governments, as well as
representatives of several civic organizations.</P>
      <P>Currently, the number of foreign and mainland Chinese brides
living in Taiwan is nearly 300,000.</P>
      <P>The MOI move comes in the wake of a case occurring earlier this
year in which a Vietnamese bride was maltreated by her Taiwanese
husband, resulting in outrage among Vietnamese people.</P>
      <P>The MOI decided at the meeting to cooperate with foreign
representative offices in Taiwan to offer information about Taiwan's
traditions and immigration laws, as well as information related to
the rights and obligations of foreign brides, before they come to the
island, in a bid to shorten the time takes them to adjust to Taiwan
society.</P>
      <P>Concerning the children born to these foreign brides, the
Ministry of Education will hold meetings regularly with teachers to
study and present the best educational services to these so-called
"new Taiwanese."</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0044" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>MAC PLANS TO REPATRIATE MORE ILLEGAL MAINLAND IMMIGRANTS SEPT. 10</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug.  31 (CNA)
(By Sofia Wu)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>The Mainland Affairs Council (MAC) is
scheduled to repatriate another batch of illegal mainland Chinese
immigrants Sept. 10, a senior official said Tuesday.</P>
      <P>MAC Chairman Joseph Wu made the remarks during an informal
meeting with local reporters on the eve of Taiwan's Journalist's Day.</P>
      <P>After a five-month hiatus, Taiwan managed to repatriate 178
illegal mainland immigrants Tuesday from the frontline island of
Matsu, which lies closer to the mainland than to Taiwan.</P>
      <P>Wu said there are still 2,634 illegal mainland immigrants being
held at various detention centers.</P>
      <P>"We hope mainland China can cooperate with us so that all illegal
immigrants can be repatriated as soon as possible, " Wu said, adding
that another group of illegals are scheduled to be repatriated Sept.
10.</P>
      <P>With the approach of the Mid-Autumn Festival, a traditional
family reunion day for Chinese people that falls Sept. 28 this year,
Wu said he hopes the mainland authorities will step up preparations
for accepting the repatriation of all the illegals.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0045" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>CANCELLATION OF MILITARY DRILL DISPLAYS TAIWAN'S GOODWILL: CABINET</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug. 31 (CNA)
(By Flor Wang)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>President Chen Shui-bian's cancellation of
an annual live-fire military exercise is a display of Taiwan's
goodwill and desire to build peace with mainland China, Executive
Yuan spokesman Chen Chi-mai said Tuesday.</P>
      <P>Chen said that the cancellation of the joint forces live-fire
exercise, the final part of the Hankuang No. 20 maneuvers that was
originally slated for Sept. 9 in southern Taiwan, is in line with the
basic tone set by the president in his May 20 inaugural speech.</P>
      <P>Claiming that Taiwan will fully engage in making peace across the
Taiwan Strait, Chen called for early negotiations with the mainland
to better maintain and secure peace between the two sides by reducing
tension and miscalculations.</P>
      <P>However, the Cabinet spokesman still issued a reminder urging the
Taiwan people not to underestimate the mainland's non-military
offensive through psychological, legal and public opinion fronts to
achieve its unification purpose.</P>
      <P>Although it seems that the mainland has pulled out troops from
Dongshan Island, where it had planned to carry out a military
maneuver in early September, Chen pointed out that according to
reliable information, other military exercises in other regions over
the past two months have not been scaled down.</P>
      <P>President Chen announced Monday the cancellation of the military
drill in the wake of a media report that the People's Liberation Army
had withdrawn about 3,000 troops from Dongshan Island, where it was
to have conducted a simulated attack on Taiwan.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0046" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>MAC CHIEF CONFIDENT OF COPING WITH NEW MAINLAND PROPAGANDA DRIVE</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug.  31 (CNA)
(By Sofia Wu)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>Mainland Affairs Council (MAC) Chairman
Joseph Wu said Tuesday he is confident that Taiwan can cope with
mainland China's new "united front" tactics that reportedly will
focus on winning the hearts and minds of southern Taiwan residents.</P>
      <P>Quoting a Ministry of National Defense (MND) report, Wu said
mainland China will launch a new "united front" propaganda campaign
in an attempt to defuse southern Taiwan people's hostility toward the
mainland.</P>
      <P>According to the MND report, mainland China will step up efforts
to court southern Taiwan residents through increased contacts and
engagements with grassroots farmers' associations and religious
groups.</P>
      <P>Wu said that mainland might have become aware that southern
Taiwan people are more hostile than elsewhere in the country through
the results of Taiwan's recent political elections, including the
bitterly fought presidential elections of 2000 and 2004.</P>
      <P>As a result, he said, Beijing has decided to step up a "united
front" propaganda campaign to woo southern Taiwan residents.</P>
      <P>Given Taiwan's open, liberal and pluralistic society, Wu said,
the mainland might be able to find easy access to local society.</P>
      <P>"Our competitive edge lies in our liberal lifestyle, pluralism
and openness. Mainland Chinese visitors will be able to gain a taste
of freedom, vitality and vibrancy during their stays here. In the
long run, we hope to help sow the seeds of democracy on the mainland
through increased civilian exchanges," Wu explained.</P>
      <P>Except for a small group of aboriginal tribes, most of Taiwan's
23 million people are ethnic Chinese. But the population can be
divided into two ethnic sub-groups -- the "mainlanders" whose
families fled to Taiwan when the Chinese communists took over the
mainland in 1949, and the "native Taiwanese" whose ancestors began
arriving on the island in the 17th century or earlier.</P>
      <P>The mainlanders, about 15 percent of the population, have largely
supported the opposition Kuomintang and its ally, the People First
Party, and their support base is in northern Taiwan. The native
Taiwanese control the south, and they tend to favor President Chen
Shui-bian's Democratic Progressive Party and the smaller Taiwan
Solidarity Union.</P>
      <P>The mainlanders have traditionally supported eventual unification
with the mainland, while the native Taiwanese are said by some to
lean more toward formal independence.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0047" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>GOVERNMENT TO ESTABLISH STABLE CROSS-STRAIT INTERACTION FRAMEWORK</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug.  31 (CNA)
(By Huang Kwang-chun)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>The government is seeking to gradually
establish a stable and peaceful cross-Taiwan Strait interaction
framework through talks with Beijing based on the principle of
equality, according to a written administrative report by the
Executive Yuan.</P>
      <P>The report, attached to a budget proposal for the central
government for 2005, was sent to the Legislative Yuan for its
reference. The legislature will open its new session in mid-September
and screening the government's budget for next year will be one of
its top priorities.</P>
      <P>In order to achieve the goal, the report said, the government
will continue to promote the normalization of cross-strait trade and
economic relations, try to start negotiations on the opening of
direct cross-strait trade, transportation and postal services -- the
so-called three links, gradually open up investment in Taiwan to the
mainland and take concrete measures to allow more mainland people to
visit Taiwan for commercial and tourism purposes.</P>
      <P>In addition, the government will integrate the public and private
sectors to balance and upgrade the quality of cross-strait cultural
and educational exchanges under the principles of equality, dignity,
active opening, effective management, Taiwan first, peace and
reciprocity.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0048" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>INDEPENDENT LAWMAKER SENTENCED TO 13 YEARS IN PRISON</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei,  Aug.  31 (CNA)
(By Maubo Chang)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>Independent lawmaker Yen Ching-piao of
Taichung County was sentenced Tuesday to 13 years in prison for
corruption and attempted murder while serving as a councilor in
Taichung County between 1996 and 2000.</P>
      <P>The sentence handed down by the Taichung Branch Office of the
Taiwan High Court found Yen guilty of spending NT$35 million (US$1.02
million) in public funds from the Taichung County council on dining
from 1998 to December 2000, when he served as council speaker.</P>
      <P>The deputy speaker of the Taichung county council at the time,
Chang Ching-tang, as well as then-secretary-general of the council,
Tsai Wen-hsiung, were sentenced to eight years and nine years,
respectively, as accomplices in the case.</P>
      <P>The three defendants were also ordered by court to repay the
NT$35 million.</P>
      <P>Yen was also found guilty of attempted murder for a shooting that
took place in January, 1996. The court found that Yen ordered his
four bodyguards to open fire with an assault rifle and handguns on a
car driven by a person who Yen suspected of having tried to blackmail
him.</P>
      <P>In two previous trials, Yen was found guilty on both charges and
was given jail terms of 20 years and 11-and-a-half years,
respectively.</P>
      <P>Although Yen was taken into custody, he ran in absentia for a
lawmaker seat in 2001 and won a seat in the Legislative Yuan.</P>
      <P>He was released on bail in 2002 after being found guilty of
corruption and attempted murder in the second trial and became the
leader of the 13-member Alliance of Independent Legislators at the
Legislative Yuan recently.</P>
      <P>Yen could not be reached for comment Tuesday, but one of his
aides said the sentence will not discourage Yen from serving his
homeland and that he will appeal.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0049" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>VP CHAIRS MEETING OF DPP CENTRAL STANDING COMMITTEE FOR FIRST TIME</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei, Aug. 31 (CNA)
(By Maubo Chang)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>Vice President Annette Lu chaired a meeting
of the ruling Democratic Progressive Party's (DPP's) Central Standing
Committee in the place of President Chen Shui-bian Tuesday for the
first time. Chen is also the DPP chairman.</P>
      <P>Emerging from her debut as acting chairwoman of the DPP Standing
Committee, Lu told waiting journalists that it was an exciting and
pleasant experience and that the discussion at the meeting was brisk.</P>
      <P>Legislator Trong Chai, who is a member of the DPP Central
Standing Committee, said the meeting was successful and that the
atmosphere was much easier than when Chen presides, probably, he
said, because Lu is female.</P>
      <P>Lawmaker and Central Standing Committee member Ker Chien-ming
said the meeting attendees, who tend to be more cautiously when
speaking at meetings chaired by Chen, spoke more freely at Tuesday's
meeting.</P>
      <P>DPP Deputy Secretary-General Chung Chia-ping told journalists
after the meeting that Lu issued two instructions after the
discussion, the first of which reconfirmed the party's opposition to
a statute railroaded through by the opposition for the formation of a
committee to investigate the March 19 shooting of Chen and herself.</P>
      <P>Decrying the statute as unconstitutional, Lu said the DPP cannot
yield to the abuse of legislative power by the opposition, which
controls the Legislative Yuan.</P>
      <P>In her second instruction, Lu called on the police to solve the
March 19 shooting as soon as possible in order to preempt the
opposition's attempts to interfere with the investigation by a
committee formed on their terms.</P>
      <P>As a member of the DPP Central Standing Committee, Lu was asked by
Chen to take his place at the meeting during his visit to Panama.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
  <DOC id="CNA_ENG_20040831.0050" type="story">
    <HEADLINE>EVENT LISTING FOR SEPT. 1 IN TAIWAN</HEADLINE>
    <DATELINE>Taipei, Aug. 31 (CNA)</DATELINE>
    <TEXT>
      <P>The following are major events scheduled to
take place Wednesday, Sept. 1:</P>
      <P>08: 00, The registration of legislators for the new session will
begin at the Legislative Yuan.</P>
      <P>08:40, Presidential Office Secretary-General Su Tseng-chang will
start a visit to Tainan City and Tainan County.</P>
      <P>09: 00, The weekly Cabinet meeting will be held at the Executive
Yuan.</P>
      <P>09: 00, The opposition Kuomintang will hold its Central Standing
Committee meeting at the party's headquarters.</P>
      <P>09:00, The Fourth Asia Open Source Software Conference will open
at the Howard Hotel in Taipei.</P>
      <P>09: 30, Vice President Annette Lu will chair a seminar on soil
conservation and national security at the Presidential Office.</P>
      <P>11: 00, A news conference on the behavior of Taiwan web surfers
will be held at the Market Intelligence Center under the Institute
for Information Industry.</P>
      <P>12: 15, The Taiwan delegation to the Athens Olympic Games will
hold a news conference at the Chiang Kai-shek International Airport.</P>
      <P>12: 30, The Bureau of Standards, Metrology and Inspection under
the Ministry of Economic Affairs will hold a news conference at the
Administration Building at No. 4, Chinan Rd. Sec. 1.</P>
      <P>12: 30, The National Science Council will hold a news conference
at the council's headquarters.</P>
      <P>14: 00, Vice President Annette Lu will meet members of a ruling
party faction at the Presidential Office.</P>
      <P>14: 30, The Ministry of Foreign Affairs will host a tea party at
the ministry's headquarters to mark Journalist's Day.</P>
      <P>15: 00, The Livestock Research Institute under the Council of
Agriculture (COA) will hold a news conference at the COA
headquarters.</P>
      <P>15:30, Vice President Annette Lu will receive Taiwan's delegation
to the Athens Olympic Games at the Presidential Office.</P>
      <P>16: 00, The Financial Supervision Commission will hold a news
conference at the commission's headquarters.</P>
      <P>16: 20, The Central Bank of China will hold a news conference at
the bank's headquarters.</P>
      <P>16:30, The Ministry of Finance will hold a news conference at the
ministry's headquarters.</P>
      <P>18: 00, Premier Yu Shyi-kun will host a dinner party for the
Taiwan delegation to the Athens Olympic Games at the Armed Forces
Heroes Hall in Taipei.</P>
    </TEXT>
  </DOC>
</GWENG>
